My family lineage is settlers from the
1500s.
>> Colonialists.
>> Yeah, colonialist.
>> You don't look very Native American to
me.
>> Native I am Native American. Whites are
Native Americans. What are you talking
about?
>> What are you talking about?
>> You're a little bit more than a farright
Republican.
>> Hey, what can I say?
>> I think you can say I'm a fascist.
>> Yeah, I am.
>> Listen to me. I am an immigrant. I'm
speaking from personal experience. I
don't even like
>> I should get the hell out. Why?
>> I don't want you here.
>> I'm Mandy Hassan. I'm a journalist. I'm
the editor of Zateo. And today I'm
surrounded by 20 farright conservatives.
My first claim is Donald Trump is pro-
crime and procriminal.
>> Welcome.
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you. I'm Eddie. Uh, I would
just like to ask, um, what makes someone
pro crime versus, you know, anti-rime?
>> I think when you're soft on criminals,
when you let criminals out of prison,
when you pardon people who assaulted
police officers, you're pro- criminal.
Donald Trump pardoned almost 1,600
people who were involved in January the
6th. I think 600 of them had been
charged with assaulting a police officer
or obstructing a police officer. 170 had
plead guilty to assaulting a police
officer. 70 had plead guilty to assault
with a deadly weapon. JD Vance said,
"We're not going to pardon the violent
criminals from January 6th." Donald
Trump pardoned all of them. Are you okay
with that?
>> Uh, I would say January 6th is a very
special case. I would say it's a very
it's almost a a climax point in history,
I would just phrase the question this
way. Right now in the LA protest, if
they were to
just for example, they were to rush the
capital of LA, I mean, they'd have to
move over all the homeless people living
in tents on the steps of the capital.
But if they were managed to get into the
capitol and they were just protesting,
you know, peacefully, let's say police
officers were rushing them in. They were
letting them in and saying, "Hey, you
guys can go in." Like we have many
testimonies that say,
>> "What about the violent ones, though?"
>> Okay, violent ones like
>> like a man named David Dempsey, a judge,
a Reagan appointed judge sentenced him
to 20 years in prison. He stomped on
police officers heads. The judge said
his conduct was exceptionally egregious.
He attacked police officers with flag
poles and pepper spray. Donald Trump
pardoned him. There's a man named Daniel
Rodriguez. He got 12 years in prison for
taking a stun gun and tasing a police
officer in the neck and giving him a
heart attack. The judge said he was a
one-man army of hate. Donald Trump
pardoned him. Does that not make Trump
procriminal?
>> He's letting violent criminals out of
prison.
>> I would say no. It doesn't make him
procriminal. One You're okay with that?
I did not say that. I said that one
pardon against somebody.
>> It was 1,600 pardons. 600 those were
charged.
>> One example that you just gave me.
>> I can give you more. I keep going. Fine.
Fine. And I'll say the exact same thing
every single time. your argument will
fall apart because it's not just one
example if I keep going.
>> Go for it then.
>> Okay. Shane Jenkins got seven years in
prison for nine criminal offenses,
attacking police with a deadly weapon,
destroying government property pardons
that probably shouldn't have happened
turn into proime.
>> So you've agreed that they shouldn't
have been pardoned.
>> Sure. But that wasn't your claim was
January 6. Your claim was Trump is pro
crime.
>> Yeah. Because he pardons criminals.
>> Okay. I would pardon Let's talk about
non- January 6 people. He's pardoned
people like Paul Walsh recently who took
millions of dollars from his own
employees, was sentenced to tax crimes,
had to pay back $4 million. Trump
pardoned him. He bought himself a $2
million yacht. Why is he pardoning
criminals like that?
>> Uh, well, I don't know. I don't think
you should I don't think really
presidential pardon should be a thing at
all. But I don't think I don't think
that means something.
>> You've been voted out by the majority.
Please return to your seat.
>> Thanks.
>> How's it going? Hey, how's it going?
Medi,
>> what is it?
>> Medi,
>> you're from Northern UK, I guess.
>> I'm from London, North London.
>> Okay, fair enough. What's your ethnic
background if you don't mind asking?
>> My parents are from India.
>> Okay, perfect. Just getting premise
here. First of all, I want to say
>> the premise of Donald Trump being pro
crime.
>> No, no, no. I want to concern myself
with why you care about what's happening
in the US first and foremost. Secondly,
I want to say this with the argument
like
>> should people who live in the US or
let's not interrupt each other because
I'm I have this thing like people know I
have this thing I have to stay calm.
Okay. So,
>> okay.
>> Here's the thing. I am happy that he
released J6. In fact, so much so that I
was prepared to protest if he didn't.
Okay. So, when you say are you okay that
he's pro- crime? Sure. Because you know
what? We're changing the definition of
what crime is first and foremost.
>> You don't think stomping on police
officers heads is a crime? I don't think
it's it's it's no longer a relevant
conversation anymore. You're arguing.
No, it's not because you know what?
Okay. Have you seen the US in the last
four or five years, BLM protests? Have
you seen Okay. I myself have been
involved in these protests. I've seen
egregious things, things that you
couldn't even imagine
to conservatives. It's not about that.
It's about tribal warfare. That's where
we're at in the US. I don't know where
you're at in the UK. You're from India,
so I don't really
>> I'm not from India.
>> Oh, sorry. Your parents are from India.
So, you have your own stakes.
>> I'm an American. You know,
>> you're an American citizen. Okay, fair
enough. I don't know how you got that,
but fair enough. Here's the thing.
>> Are you an American citizen?
>> Absolutely.
>> But here's the thing.
>> Not sure how you got that. Okay.
>> Born here.
>> Okay.
>> Born here. And my my family lineage is
settlers from the 1500s. So, I have some
stake in in the claim here. Okay. A
little different.
>> But you're a descendant of immigrants.
Settlers.
>> Colonialists.
>> Yeah. Colonial.
>> You don't look very Native American to
me.
>> Native. I am Native American. Whites are
Native Americans. What are you talking
about?
>> What are you talking about?
>> Whites are Native Americans.
>> Really? I I think
>> what was happening before the 1500s I
think you're getting confused with
>> I don't mind going on a tangent what was
happening before the 1500s calm down I
think you're getting what was happening
before the 1500s
>> uh there was indigenous people here that
came here from
>> you know what indigenous means
>> listen before
>> indigenous people come from somewhere
else why do you ask a question if you're
going to interrupt
>> I'm not sure if you know what the
meaning of indigenous means
>> I do know what it means means they came
here first right they came here from
Asia by way of landbridgeidge have an
argument with Neil deGrasse Tyson or
anybody else about that I don't care I
genuinely don't care yes he is okay.
>> My my point is my point is okay
>> nothing to do with crime. So far you've
agreed with me that these people
>> you're derailing dude. I'm like I'm
trying to
>> literally sat down and ask me where I'm
from. I think you derailed this
conversation from the get by that. But
I'm
>> not offended. I'm just wondering what it
has to do with crime. Always curious.
>> We're going to talk about immigration.
Don't worry. Later on you can come back.
>> I hope so.
>> Right now you're doing a very bad job of
making the case that he's not pro crime.
>> Got a round of applause. I probably get
another one actually if I ask for it. So
So I I don't think you get rounds of
applause. You sit in a room with 20
people who agree with you. Wow. Amazing.
Amazing. That must be
>> this comes out. You know what? I'm
actually 20 people who agree with you.
Personally outraged right now. This is
this is great. Do I have to say anything
at this point or you just going to keep
going?
>> Please make make your claim.
>> Well, my claim is that I don't care if
it's pro crime. You want to go back to
the topic of conversation?
>> That's fine. We agree then crime.
>> I have a question for you though. Do you
care on the opposite side of the
spectrum? Yes.
>> Do you care about law being administered
to the opposite side of the spectrum? I
think anyone who assaults a police
officer shouldn't be pardoned. I think
that Donald Trump shouldn't have
pardoned nine Republican members of
Congress who were convicted of crimes.
And I don't think Joe Biden should
commit I don't think Democrats should
pardon Democrats.
>> Fair, but I don't think you understand
where we are in the US. That
>> I think I do.
>> No, because you're arguing from the
position of like an a US that doesn't
exist anymore. We're headed towards
>> So nihilism, no laws, nothing matters.
Everyone's
>> program. It's not about that. It's that
conservatives for Listen, conservatives
for too long have been playing it safe.
They've been playing by the law. They've
been playing by the law. Yes, they have.
>> Maybe you missed the Bush presidency.
Did you live here during the Bush years?
>> Conservative conservatives are play by
the law. George W. Bush, nor did Ronald
Reagan.
>> Let's be Let's be respectful to you.
Let's let me
>> I'm not sure you've been that
respectful, but Okay.
>> I'm trying to bring it back. So, let's
both bring it back. Okay.
>> I'm conservative. Okay.
>> Really?
>> Let me tell you this. We do play it too
safe. We've been playing it by the book
for too long. At this point, gloves are
off, right? The left has made their
point. They're willing to
>> The police force in Washington. The
left.
>> Are you kidding me? The left. Are you
are you in police officers?
>> Look Okay, look at LA right here. You
think those standown uh those standown
>> You think the LAPD are a bunch of
liberal Marxists?
>> No, but I think they listen to liberal
Marxists who tell them what to do.
>> I I think they listen to who signs their
paychecks at the end of the day. You're
doing lots of little diversions. We both
agree Donald Trump's prom. You're just
fine with it. That's what you said so
far.
>> I don't agree with your I don't agree
with your definition.
>> What's your definition of crime?
Stomping on a police officer's head is
not a crime. That's your definition of
crime as the Native American.
>> I am Native American if you say so.
>> So, going back to the topic at hand, we
have different definitions of crime
because you're talking about
>> there's a criminal code in this country.
It's called the US criminal code.
>> You know what? Let's focus on what we
agree on. I'm sure you and I actually
agree on a lot.
>> Do we agree that people shouldn't stomp
on police officers heads? Can we agree
on that? If you don't agree on that,
then I really think this conversation is
kind of
>> No, because first of all, you're saying
what? That the police have the authority
that they're given the authority. I
don't accept the authority that's been
given by liberals conservative position.
>> The conservative a pro police
>> then you don't know what a real Hey,
listen. You're juggernauts right now.
I'm telling you right now, you are going
to be blown open. If you think that
>> we're going to struggle with the English
language for the next couple hours, then
what you're up against right now, okay?
Yeah. News flash, the conservatives are
liberal to me. Okay. Neocons,
libertarians, all those mainstream
people, there might as well be leftists
to me. Okay, that's how far to the right
I am. Do you understand my position? So
when you say I kind of guessed it when
you said that when you say uh you know
about obeying police, why would I give
the authority to police? Do you know do
you know you're an American do you think
Donald Trump should be pardoning nine
members of Congress who committed
financial crimes? Are you are you pro
financial crime? You pro financial crime
Timbo is pause.
>> I think the people who clapped you have
voted you out.
>> All right, head back to your seat.
You've been voted out by the majority.
>> Nice to meet you.
Hi there.
>> Hi sir, how are you?
>> Hey, so I'm going to be as respectful
about this as possible, but the truth is
your claim is completely bad faith. You
do not care about being anti-rime. You
yourself are pro crime. Your side is pro
crime because you're a progressive.
>> How am I proimer?
>> So I'll give you an example, right? So
your side, not Donald Trump, has passed
a series of laws in California. Let's go
with California. It's where we are right
now. It's where I'm from. I don't Are
you from California or Okay. So in
California, for example, the state
legislature, completely progressive,
just passed a law that limits sex
offender registration to 10 years. It
was life before. That's proime. The
legislature in California, which is
progressives again, has passed a law
that says the voter induced three strike
law is no longer absolute. If someone
attempt murders someone, stabs someone
on three separate occasions, a judge now
does not have to give them life. That's
a progressive law. That is not that is
proime. You support that, don't you? I
>> actually don't support uh sex offenders
coming off a list. I think they should
be on for life.
>> Okay. So, you disagree with you and so
so hold on. You and I both agree that
sex offending is a bad thing, especially
child sex offending. Right.
>> It seems like you and I agree on that.
California doesn't.
>> So, I'm not here to debate the
legislative California. I'm here to
debate Donald Trump being pro crime. And
I'm saying I'm saying that Donald Trump
was friends with Gileain Maxwell when
Gileain Maxwell who's the worst child
sex trafficker of our lifetime. She's
serving over 20. Do you know Gain
Maxwell?
>> Yeah. She's actually not. Jeffrey
Epste's the worst sex.
>> He's dead. I'm talking about people are
alive right now.
>> It's interesting though you didn't use
his name, right? Wouldn't he be the one
who did this?
>> Oh, great. Hey, I'm glad you brought up
Jeffrey Epste. Jeffrey Epste before he
died did an interview with Michael Wolf.
He's on tape. I don't know if you've
heard the tape. He says, "My closest
friend was Donald Trump. I was his
closest friend." Uh Elon Musk, I'm not
sure if you've heard of him. He tweeted
recently that Donald Trump's name is in
the Epstein files. And Gileain Maxwell,
who was the right-hand woman of Jeffrey
Epstein, when she was on trial for child
sex offending, which you and I are
opposed to. Donald Trump stood up and
said, "Good luck to her. I wish her
well." So, yeah, that makes him pro
crime and procriminal if he's being soft
on child sex traffickers. Like Epste
was friends. He was friends with Epste.
You haven't seen the videos. They dance
together, party together. He knows he's
not supported the pedophilia part. The
only people true. Trump gave a speech
about 20 years ago where he said
Epstein's a great guy. He loves young
women. A lot of them are very young.
Nudge, nudge, wink, wink, laugh, laugh.
So yeah, I think he's pro crime and pro
criminals. I think Do you have any
friends who are criminals?
>> Not that I know of. Certainly not child
sex offenders. No. Do you?
>> If it came No, of course not.
>> Okay. So, we're both in agreement again.
If
>> it came out tomorrow that one If it came
out tomorrow that one of your friends
was a child sex traff, you'd stop being
friends with them. But I wouldn't say
>> and then I'd go on TV and I would say,
"Oh, look, Mr. Hassan was friends with
this guy 10 years ago. Therefore, he's
trial." Mr. Hassan said, "I wish them
well when they're on trial." Wouldn't
you ever have a go at me for that?
>> You wish your well you wish your friend
well on trial.
>> Yeah. Child sex trafficker. Would you
mean that?
>> I wouldn't wish someone well, but that's
your that's your gotcha.
>> It's a pretty big wish.
>> Pretty big gotcha. He praised what
you're really trying to do right now. Is
your Donald Trump
says his name? What's his policy?
>> You want to talk policies? So when he
left office in 2020, he left behind the
highest murder rate for over 100 years.
>> He left behind the highest murder. That
is the most bad faith claim you could
possibly make.
>> It's a fact from the CDC.
>> You know what? Here's why it's bad
faith. I'm Can I finish the sentence?
And then you come back in.
>> You're just lying to people. Donald
Trump lying. Can I finish the sentence?
>> Donald Trump does not cause the murder
rate. Murder is a state level. That's
hilarious. Gavin Newsome is more
responsible for the murder rate than
Donald Trump is. That's hilarious. So
Donald Trump's not responsible murder
rate, but other politicians who are
Democrats because it's a state law.
That's like saying no. That's No, I'll
say Republicans are too. State governors
who are soft on crime are the ones that
are responsible.
Who's doing the murdering?
>> The murderers.
>> So, aren't they responsible for
>> Why did it go up on his watch?
>> What?
>> Why did it go up on his watch? He's very
bad. That's fighting crime.
>> That's a real hard one to figure out,
right? We shut down the whole economy
during COVID. We told everyone they
couldn't go out unless it was to
violently protest. We told people that
if a cop tries to arrest you, that cop's
probably going to get charged with
murder.
>> No, I think the pandemic had a lot to do
with it. The pandemic didn't finish in
2020. What?
>> The pandemic didn't finish in 2020.
>> Why the murder rate? If we're going to
play the one, you guys blame Joe Biden
for crime for years.
>> What? Joe Biden actively induces
policies that are pro crime. I'm asking
Donald Trump. Name the policy that's
crime. I'll blame I've asked you for
like 10 minutes. I'll name one right
now. No, you haven't. You talked about
California legislatores. Um he pardoned
violent criminals. He then went on to
commit other crimes. You don't think
releasing violent crimes into
>> pardon is a one time thing. What's his
policy he has pushed? Name a law he has.
>> No. A pardon is a one time thing is a
policy is not one time thing.
>> That's like Jimmy Carter pardon the
draft.
>> They want to dodge January 6 the pardon.
>> I'm not judging that. Did you write a
Jimmy Carter pardon? Does that mean his
policy was support? Do you support Do
you support the pardoning of people who
went on to be prosecuted for sexually
abusing a seven-year-old child, illegal
gun possession, reckless homicide?
There's more. See, there's more. He
didn't pardon someone for sexually
abusing a child someone for rebelling
against the government that they believe
had rigged elections. That's what he
pardoned them for. He didn't pardon them
for sexual child abuse.
>> But they were criminals who committed
those crimes. He let them out. So that
means the crime rate goes up.
>> Here's a You say they're criminals
because they did the crime, right? Would
you extend that to illegal immigrants
that they're all criminals because they
committed a crime? I have a feeling your
position the Supreme Court Supreme Court
we're going to talk about immigration
>> someone who's illegally entered the
United States not a criminal but someone
capital is not according to Supreme
Court of the United States
>> the Supreme Court has said that anyone
who enters the United States illegally
and we can we can jump to Can I get the
case? Can I get the case?
>> Jump to You want to get the case
>> the case the case site please for you
said the Supreme Court
>> the citation of the case.
>> Yes. That entering the United States
illegally is not a crime.
>> It's called Arizona versus United States
2012. Go look it up.
>> Pause. You've been voted out by the
majority. Please return to your seat.
Hey, how's it going?
>> How you doing, sir?
>> Nice to meet you, M. Nice to meet you.
Thank you for coming. I appreciate you.
>> I really just more want to get an
understanding. When you say procriminal,
what do you mean?
>> I mean that when confronted with people
who've committed criminal acts, Donald
Trump has been either soft on them,
friendly with them, pardon them, and of
course, let's not forget, I mean, we've
got five minutes left. I'm surprised it
hasn't come up earlier. He's a convicted
criminal himself sitting in the White
House. Okay. I want to make sure I
understand you correctly because I don't
want to straw man you. You're saying
>> I appreciate that.
>> Every time that he's been confronted,
>> not every time. Don't say the words
every time.
>> Most times. A lot of the time.
>> A lot of the times.
>> He's leaned towards criminal activity.
>> I didn't say criminal activity. He I
mean he has committed crimes. He's been
indicted for 88 different criminal
offenses in four different jurisdictions
by five different grand juries. He was
convicted himself on 34 different
criminal offenses by a jury of his
peers. But let's part that for a moment.
separate to his own crimes. When
confronted with the crimes of others or
the alleged crimes of others, for
example, a Chinese crypto billionaire
called Justin Sun who was being
investigated for market manipulation,
Trump dropped the case, invited him to
the golf course, invited him to the
White House
$70 million in Trump's crypto. What I
want to ask you, proime in my view,
>> is it possible because remember the
burden of proof's on you, right? You
have to prove. Is it possible that all
these these things that he's done that
supposedly make him pro crime is there's
another reason for the for the doing?
There's other justification for example
for let me let me give an example and
then you can about it
>> the J6 is it possible that he could have
done this to unite the country to move
past to go to a new chapter if it's even
possible I think you would have to admit
that there's another possibility
therefore he's not pro crime
>> at least possibility
>> so let me agree and disagree with
>> so I agree with you that the intent
could be different I don't think Donald
Trump was sitting there saying how can I
increase the level of murders let me
release some murderers I'm not saying he
did that on January 6
>> I don't think he was trying to unite the
country. That's where we disagree.
That's In fact, he divided the
country further. But intent doesn't
really matter to my claim. If he's
releasing violent criminals,
>> wait in doesn't matter.
>> No, he's pro- crime and pro criminal.
>> No, but that's a big indictment to say
pro crime. That means crime.
>> I'm fronted. If Well, he is because for
I gave him No, no, no. It could be
possible. Sorry. Forgive me.
>> Your friend earlier, your ally said, uh,
where has he done stuff that's increased
the crime? I'm telling you, people have
been pardoned who have been convicted on
multiple other crimes. These people who
he pardoned had previous criminal
records. They were not just some folks
chilling around go, we're against the
take over our country. We're opposed to
rebellion. They were a lot of these
people were already hardened criminals,
militia members. He looked at those
people and said, you know what, they've
been convicted in many cases by
Republican judges,
>> but I'm going to let them out. Yeah,
that makes
>> Is it possible? And if Joe Biden had
done it, you'd be attacking him.
>> Sure. Is it possible that their
conviction was part of a plea? It's
like, "Oh I can't get out of this,
so I got to take a plea deal."
>> Some of them maybe, others, others we
saw with our own lying eyes on tape,
battering police officers. I mean, did
you watch Did you watch live on January
6th? What happened?
>> To be completely honest, I'm pretty
novice on this. I'm more trying to
target. You're saying he's pro crime in
my head just thinking this live. Let me
finish back for one second. If thinking
this, there's a possibility that he
might have had other reasons. For
example, unifying the country next
chapter, right? That that could be the
reason. Therefore, it's not pro- crime.
There was other reasons. I'm just saying
that's a possibility. And if that's
>> I'm saying it's a possibility, but I'm
saying it's irrelevant because if you
are releasing knowingly releasing
violent criminals out into the
community, pardoning, not just
releasing, then yes, you are being
procriminal. And I've interviewed police
officers. I don't know about that. I've
interviewed police officers who have
been assaulted, beaten, had to retire
from the police office, broken bones.
Let me say that. I'll finish very
quickly. I've interviewed these police
officers. They've been beaten by people
who they've then seen walk off the
streets and then carry on threatening
them. Yes. When Donald Trump is
responsible for that, you're definitely
pro crime.
>> Okay. I I I doubt a lot of the sources,
but
>> you doubt police officers who testified
to being assaulted.
>> You've been voted out by the majority.
Please return to your seat.
>> Thanks.
>> Hey, how's it going?
>> Good. How are you?
>> Nice to meet you, Maddie. Um, so you
claim that your main claim is that Trump
pardoned some people from January 6. By
the way, I was there. Um, I saw it all
firsthand. Uh, about a football field
away. There's smoke in my eyes, a
bloodied. It was It was a crazy day.
>> Were you convicted of any crimes?
>> No, of course not, cuz I didn't enter
the building. Um, you know, stayed very
peaceful.
>> Um, but your entire claim is that he
pardons your bets basically. You keep
bringing it up. All you do is bring it
up. I'll mention Let me say this. I'm
okay with his pardoning of Paul Walch
who from his employees. You keep talking
about nine former members of Congress.
That's why he keeps pardoning criminals.
That makes him
>> You know who else pardoned? A big
criminal.
>> Go on.
>> Hunter Biden was pardoned by his father.
He did crack cocaine and he had hookers
there, too.
>> I'm with you all. I'm with you all.
>> But then why don't you claim that Biden
Why don't you claim that
>> I think Joe Biden in that instant was
programmed. He shouldn't have done it.
>> Well, he was overall pro just because he
did that.
>> No, but Joe Biden didn't just So Joe So
if it was just a pardon, then you'd be
fine. But I already mentioned there's
also the fact that Joe Biden wasn't
actually convicted criminal in office.
Trump has committed crimes. Trump hangs
around with criminals. He spent much of
the 80s hanging around with the New York
mob. He hung around with Jeffrey Epste
and Gileain Maxwell.
>> Well, that whole that I can keep going.
>> Jeffrey Epstein lived in West Palm Beach
to the area and that's the closest golf
course he go to. Do you think he's very
paid? Do you think Donald Trump is as
soon as Trump found out? Do you think
Donald Trump is in the Epstein?
>> No, I do not. And you're on. Let me
explain. Let me explain this. Okay.
>> He lived in the area in Mara Lago near
Mara Lago. So he bought obviously uh
ticket to go in there. As soon as Trump
found out that Epstein had done all
those bad things, immediate ban from
immediate ban from Yes, it is. Yes, it
is. In fact, Gile recruited some of the
girls that were abused from Maraago.
>> So um so listen to this.
>> From Mara. That's pretty outrageous,
right?
>> Elon Musk tweeted that out in fit of
rage. Okay. Do you really tell the truth
when they're angry? The truth comes out
when people are angry sometimes. So
Cashel Cash Patel literally said that
Elon Musk had no access to the Epstein
files. So
>> Cash Patel said that Epstein killed
himself. Do you agree with that?
>> Whatever he says goes then. Yeah, I
don't I don't care. He knows more
information than I do. A
>> lot of magic.
>> He knows more information than I do. But
but here's here's the actual claim.
>> Suddenly people are trying to vote you
out because you said you agree with Cash
Patel on Epstein.
>> I he knows more information than I do.
>> Pause. That's time. Please return to
your seat.
>> Good to meet you.
>> Yeah. Take care.
Surrounded is now a podcast available
wherever you listen. Search Surrounded,
plug in and stay part of the
conversation. Anywhere, anytime.
>> My next claim is that Donald Trump is
defying the Constitution.
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Pleasure to meet you, sir.
>> May lovely to meet you. So, I would say
that with Trump being anti-constitution,
I don't really care to be quite frankly
because in regards
in regards to the Constitution, the
Constitution is a document that should
seek to serve us. And when it fails to
seek to serve us, that can be amended.
Laws can be changed. And quite frankly,
the fact is we're defending things in
this country that shouldn't be defended.
The First Amendment should not defend
pornography and making children and
women be victimized.
making women and children be victimized
as a result of that. I think things like
blasphemy shouldn't be allowed per the
first amendment. I think that quite
frankly there are a lot of legal
processes that are enabling criminals
and bad people to fully enact their will
in this country in the name of the
constitution or following the
constitution. So quite frankly, if Trump
is anti-constitution, good. And I think
he should go further.
>> So this is this is wonderfully revealing
of the modern conservative mindset. So I
appreciate you spelling it out so
openly. Um, just checking. Do you
support the Second Amendment?
>> I do.
>> Okay. Surprise. I was shocked to hear
that. Um, I'm saying that Donald Trump
is defying the First Amendment, the
Fourth Amendment, the Fifth Amendment,
the 14th Amendment. He's thinking of
defying the 12th and 22nd amendments.
You're saying you don't care about the
Constitution, but actually you do
because you quite like the Second
Amendment. You just don't like the bits
that you disagree with. Can I just be
clear on that?
>> Yeah, absolutely. I'm more than willing
to I'm more than willing to amend it and
and
>> whenever it's in your favor.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>> So, can Democrats do the same when
they're in office?
>> No, absolutely not. Because Democracy?
>> No, I don't. Absolutely not.
>> What do you believe in?
>> Autocracy.
>> By who?
>> Honestly, quite frankly, anyone who is
in line with Catholic teaching.
>> Donald Trump is not Catholic.
>> Of course, he's not. I completely agree.
That's the problem.
>> You don't support Trump.
>> No, I don't. I didn't even vote for him.
I wrote in like John Pork or someone. I
can't even remember.
>> Why did you vote if you don't believe in
democracy and you want autocracy?
>> Well, cuz quite frankly, I voted. I kind
of voted just to
>> I came with this argument, but I'm bored
of my own argument. I'm much more
interested in this. So, absolutely.
>> How do we get to an autocracy?
>> I think quite frankly that if we are
able to enact local leaders,
>> we by the way,
>> I think quite frankly these farright
conservatives sitting right around
>> white people.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>> So, I have quite some of the people in
this room don't make the cut from what I
can see visually.
>> Actually, hold on for a moment. I do
think that there are people who happen
to not be white who do actually have
history in this country and have roots
in this country. For instance, from the
Mexican-American War, we subsumed a lot
of territory of people who have far
stakes in this country who happen to be
Hispanic or what have you. I'm for
defending the traditional demographics
of this country, which is majority
white. I should stay that way.
>> How does the United States
>> I mean, we've gone so off topic, but how
does the United States look like under
your Sorry, what's your name?
>> Um, uh, my name is, uh, well, my name's
Connor. It's a pleasure to meet you.
>> Took a little bit of a doubt there.
>> I I I use a pseudonym online. Fair
enough.
>> How would Connor<unk>'s America look?
What would it look like?
>> Well, quite frankly, I think we would
deport people who shouldn't be here.
>> I didn't ask deporting. What does the
government look like?
>> What's the government look like? I would
say quite frankly, it's under a sort of
benevolent leader such as, you know,
>> h it could be a kind of aristocratic
class. Could be someone
>> who picks the autocrat.
>> Frankly, the people. I mean, we could
hold a vote on it. Kings.
>> Isn't that democracy?
>> Well, sure. You can have a vote to get
to that state
>> and then no more votes afterwards.
>> Absolutely.
>> 100%.
>> Wow. And if that autocrat kills you and
your family, you're fine with that.
>> Well, I'm not I'm not going to be a part
of the group that he kills because
that's a whole thing. Autocrats tend to
kill everyone makes this point very well
in his work. It's the friend enemy
distinction, right? You call the Nazi
theoretician.
>> Absolutely. I don't care.
>> Are you a fan of the Nazis?
>> I don't I frankly don't care being
called the Nazi.
>> I didn't say that. I didn't say that. I
said, "Are you a fan of the Nazis?"
>> Well, they persecuted the church a
little bit. I'm not a fan of that. But
>> what about the persecution of the Jews?
>> Well, I mean, I I certainly don't
support anyone's human dignity being
assaulted. I'm a Catholic,
>> but you don't condemn Nazi persecution
of the Jews.
>> I I think that there was a little bit of
persecution rename this show because
you're a little bit more than a farright
Republican.
>> Hey, what can I say?
>> I think you can say I'm a fascist.
>> Yeah, I am.
>> Two.
>> Absolutely. I'm just checking who's
clapping just to get my set of where
everyone is on this because you know
that millions of people are going to be
watching you on YouTube and checking out
who the fascists and the Nazis are.
>> I'm I'm not ashamed of that whatsoever.
During the pre during the pre-war
period, prior to World War II, it was
only those parties that properly enacted
the people's will. That's why they won.
The conservatives were fat cats in Are
you in favor of killing people who
aren't like you?
>> Quite frankly, I'm not
>> You mentioned Franco earlier. Franco
killed a lot of innocent people.
>> Oh, well, he killed communists. He
killed people who raped nuns and killed
priests.
>> What about children who he killed and
women who he killed?
>> What are you talking about? He never
killed any women or children. He was
captive.
>> He only killed combatants. Is that what
you're claim?
>> Yeah, he only killed combatants killed
any white the white terror was only
punishing those people who did acts of
terrorism. And again, are you supporting
like raping innocent women? Nuns, dude,
killing priests. I mean, priests don't
brandish guns and killed.
>> You just refuse to condemn the Nazi
Holocaust, my friend. I don't think
you're in a position to ask anyone any
questions.
>> I I quite frankly don't care what you
think about me. If if I'm a Nazi and
being a Nazi is mutual and being a Nazi
means upholding human dignity because I
even believe in your dignity. I don't in
a state that I was running I wouldn't
want I wouldn't want to hurt you or
anything like that. But quite frankly,
>> I don't debate fascists.
>> Okay. So, do you do you concede then? I
mean, why
>> do I concede you're a fascist who won't
condemn the Nazis? Yes, I concede that.
>> Okay, great. So, I I I mean, what are we
doing here? Cuz I mean, you just seem
you just seem offended to be quite
frankly like
>> I'm offended by people who can't condemn
the Nazis. Yes, I am.
>> Okay. Well, I I condemn the evils that
they did, but I don't really care about
being Yeah, sure. I don't care though
about being called a Nazi is the whole
thing. I never called you a Nazi, a
fascist, and a General Franco.
>> Yeah, I am a General Franco supporter.
He was awesome. He was so super cool
quite frankly because the whole thing
>> And you don't believe in democracy.
>> I don't believe in democracy.
>> What are you doing here at a televised
debate?
>> This is democracy. I want a debate.
>> It is the means to support an end. The
reason we have free speech now is
because we want to be openly talking
about our opinions so we can get the
state that we want. But it doesn't mean
free speech after we win. Again, I
mentioned the only good thing about this
fascist moment. The whole reason is that
you guys are so open about it. The whole
reason
the whole reason I mentioned Carl
Schmidt earlier and you kind of blew
past him is the friend enemy
distinction.
because even liberals when they take
power, they want to enact policies and
they want to act enact protections for
their people and their ideas and they're
willing to punish their enemy. And so
I'm the same way. I'm like, "Hey, if
you're going to punish me, I'm going to
get in power and I'm going to frankly
punish you when you try to leverage
power against me." Just that simple.
>> I'm not sure what you would have said.
Hey, it is what it is.
>> All right, pause. You've been voted out
by the majority. Please return to your
seats.
>> It's a pleasure to meet you, sir. I
can't say the same, but uh thank you.
>> Good to meet you, Mandy.
>> Good to meet you, sir. All right. So, I
kind of want to start at the basics or
the foundation. I want to see
>> Can I just check? Are you a fascist?
>> No.
>> Okay. I I don't I describe myself as I
think just a Christian. I'm a fair I'm a
devout Christian.
>> Good to hear.
>> So,
um I want to start like what is your
connection to the Constitution and why
why do you love it so much? Like what
what makes it so important that Trump
would defy something like the
Constitution to you personally?
>> Great questions. Uh my first connection
is I'm an American citizen. I
naturalized American citizen. Took a
pledge uh to this country to the
Constitution. Uh, as a previous uh,
speaker has said, constitution is not
perfect. A lot of things I don't like
about it. I don't like the second
amendment. Um, there's various
amendments. I don't like the way the
Senate is set up. I'm sure there's
things you don't like about the
Constitution. The difference is, I don't
think you can just illegally defy the
Constitution. I don't think each and
every one of us can make up whatever we
want. Certainly presidents who are
elected with an oath, right? Donald
Trump took an oath to preserve, protect,
defend the Constitution. And now when
he's asked on television, "Isn't it your
job to uphold the Constitution?" He said
on NBC, "I don't know." which goes
against his oath. And I'm identifying
specific amendments where he is
violated. He's only six months into his
presidency, defying the first amendment,
the fourth amendment, the fifth
amendment, the 14th amendment. He wants
to defy the 22nd amendment and be
president for a third term. Um, this is
the problem we have right now. Free
speech is under assault. The free press
is under assault. Due process is under
assault. Uh, the right to be in your
home and not be invaded by federal
agents, the Fourth Amendment is under
assault. So, that for me is a problem.
>> Okay. Well, I'd like to start to say I
really don't find the Constitution that
important. I find it to be like a
300-year-old document. And it was
created to defy the country that
subjugated your ancestors in India. And
then your parents probably moved from
India to Britain. And then you moved
here to tell us that we should listen to
a piece of paper that you were never
even connected to to begin with. So, I
want to say like if I don't care about
it, why do you care about it so much?
>> How do you run a country without any
kind of laws or due process? And by the
way, you do care about it because
without the First Amendment, you
wouldn't be sitting here.
>> Well, I agree with the First Amendment
and I think
>> So, do you agree with Donald Trump's
crackdown on the First Amendment? He's
he's imprisoning people for their
speech. He's crack he's he's threatening
free speech media organizations. He's
threatening peaceable assembly. These
are all rights under the First
Amendment. Why aren't you bothered by
that as a conservative who claims to
love the First Amendment?
>> So, I actually I don't like the First
Amendment. And I like free speech.
>> Okay. The first amendment is what
guarantees free speech. I'm from the UK,
by the way. I'm from the UK, which is a
democracy. We don't have the first
amendment. No, that's one of the things
I do like about the constitution. I wish
the UK did have a first amendment. I'm a
journalist.
>> People arrested for praying outside
abortion clinics and stuff like that,
right?
>> So So you're you're opposed to people
being arrested for speech crimes. I
>> It depends what it is. If it's like the
people
>> So you're like one of the previous
speakers. You don't As long as it's
someone who agrees with you, you don't
mind the support.
>> Either we consistently support
principles or
>> free speech 100%. I don't think anyone.
So, do you think Donald Trump is defying
the Constitution by cracking down on the
First Amendment?
>> Um, so I think he's cracking down on
free speech like the deportation of
Mahmood Khalil, who's uh
>> who was just released from prison by a
judge saying his first amendment rights
were violating.
>> And I and I agree with the judge and I
disagree with Trump deporting them. But
I think that's more a matter of free
speech and not the constitution.
>> I think that's pedentary at this moment.
I think you've conceded that he is
cracking down on free speech which is
the first amendment. So he is defying
the constitution. So it's pleasure to be
in agreement with you, sir.
>> All right. Pause. You've been voted out
by the majority. Please return to the
>> Thank you very much.
>> How you sir?
>> I'm Medi.
>> Medie. Great to meet you. My name is
Kai.
>> Do you believe that the Constitution is
important and good
>> overall? Yes.
>> Do you believe that that constitution
can be eroded through democratic
processes?
>> What do you mean by erode? the original
intention of the Constitution being
destroyed through a purely, you know,
democratic or legal process.
>> I'm not sure I agree with that.
>> Okay.
>> I think if you're democratically
amending the Constitution per the rules
of the Constitution, that's fine. If we
could find a constitutional way to get
rid of the Second Amendment, I'd be pro
that.
>> So, let's let's pose a hypothetical
where in the entire population of the
United States has drastically changed.
Yes. And the population now um has
completely different intentions about
what to do with the country. Let's say
it wants to give it all back to Mexico,
dismantling the United States of
America. If that's the case, then what's
the use of the Constitution? It hasn't
defended the country. In fact, it's
allowed for its destruction. I don't
understand the premise. How did the
whole country change?
>> Demographic replacement, mass migration.
I mean, we're we're seeing a change in
demographics. And there there's
>> What is the
>> I do want to talk about immigration
today. We talk about everyone's itching
in this group to get immigration. I've
saved it. I've saved it for you all. But
given we're on the sense of the
Constitution and you asked a question,
what is the proportion of immigrants in
this country? um what proportion of the
population is is foreignb born.
>> It's it's very difficult to measure
because the actual projections of the
number have been changing more rapidly.
>> What is currently
>> the best estimate?
>> I think it was about 15% just under 15%
>> which is by the way which is more
actually than the original estimate was.
So
>> 15% of the people are going to change
the country, change the constitution.
How's that going? It's actually a
nightmare. As someone who wants to amend
the constitution and get rid of things
like the the ridiculous way the senate
is set up or the second amendment on
guns or various other things, it's
really hard to change the constitution.
They made it imposs almost impossible.
You know, the last time we had a
constitutional amendment like 20 30
years ago, it was I think members of
Congress pays.
Where are you getting this scenario
where 350 odd million people all become
foreignb born migrants or the children
of migrants immediate migrants even
though America is a nation of migrants
>> and then abandon the constitution and
give the country back to Mexico outside
of your imagination where is that
happening let's well let's bring it back
to the actual discussion what you did is
you you entertain my hypothetical but
then instead of sticking to the point of
the constitution you said well how would
you bring about your hypothetical and
then when I
>> because you missed out the part where
the constitution is quite hard to change
>> hold on I understand that I gave you I
also wanted to a sense of where you are
and you're a great replacement guy. So
that's fine.
>> Okay. Okay. Yeah. And you're a real good
journalist because you don't talk to
people who identify as like a political
ideology. I mean that's that's a liberal
>> I don't debate fascists. I'll talk to
them.
>> Frankly Frankly that's upsetting. I
think there's a big problem when you
know we value freedom of speech so much
but any you know real journalist is not
going to talk to somebody because they
identify with the politically incorrect
ideology.
>> Just talk to the guy in front of you.
What are you talking about?
>> You literally stop talking to him and
then debating versus talking is very
different.
>> It's pointless. He doesn't He doesn't
believe in free speech. He doesn't
believe in democracy.
>> He was freely speaking with you. You're
the one. No, he said very clearly. He
said, "I support free speech so that I
can get one election. After one
election, my guy comes in and after my
guy comes in, nobody gets to speak or
vote again. Listen to your debate that
we listen to your conversation. Let's
remind you what it was said because you
just back to the Constitution."
>> Please do. First, fourth, fifth, 14th
amendments. Those are the ones I'm
saying Trump is defying. Do you support
that or do you dy them? I believe that
the constitution is valuable because it
represents particular interests of the
founding stock of Americans who made
this country great.
>> Do you think due process is important?
Some would say that's at the very core
of American constitution amendment. And
what I think makes the constitution uh
function what allows it to save this
country and to actually make it work are
the people who are
>> I'm not sure where you're going with
this.
>> Hold on. Hold on. I'll show you the
constitution. That's my claim. You can
have these weird
>> hypothetical. We're taking it into a
different meta which is what's the
function of the constitution. I'd rather
not have your
>> You already did. You already did it just
5 minutes ago when you took it to
immigration. Okay, let's bring it back.
>> I want to bring it back to the first,
the fourth, the fifth, and the 14th
amendments and the 22nd amendments.
Either you say Hold on. You got you got
two very good positions here. One is to
say I don't think he's defying them and
I'll say why you're wrong. Or you say I
don't care that he's defying them as one
of your colleagues said in which case
>> I don't know where this conversation
goes because you don't believe in
democracy.
>> That's fair. Do you think it's wrong to
dismantle the Constitution?
>> So there are two options ahead of you.
Do you agree? This is important. Do you
agree? So, is Donald Trump okay? Let me
ask a question back since you're asking
me questions. You're not answering the
basic point. Do you think Donald Trump
is dismantling the constitution? Can we
agree that Donald Trump is dismantled?
Because I'll agree with you on that. I
think he is dismantling the
constitution. I think he's illegally
unconstitutionally interpreting it in
ways that are that are more judges do
not agree with him on.
>> Okay, which the Supreme Court has not
agreed with them on
>> and and the judges don't agree with the
people who wrote the Constitution.
>> How do you know that?
>> Okay, let's take your example of the
Second Amendment. Let's say that a bunch
of
>> I didn't give the Second Amendment. No,
first fourth. You don't want to talk
about the ones I've given.
>> You're interrupting them. You're
interrupting me. You're ignoring me.
First, fourth, fifth, 14th, 22nd
amendments. Those are my amendments that
I came with today. If you don't want to
debate them, just say so.
>> I'm trying to understand your ideology.
>> You believe that dismantling the
constitution is when it's about parts of
the constitution that you would be fine
getting rid of the second amendment even
though that would be a dismantling of
the constitution.
>> No, because it would be done via
constitutional means. I'm not the one
sitting here like your pal. You have
agreed. You have agreed the
constitution. saying you just get rid of
them willy-nilly. I don't ramping up.
>> I don't agree that Joe Biden
>> should come in and say by executive
order, if Joe Biden put out executive
order saying amendment no longer
applies, I can round up everyone's guns.
I don't agree with that.
>> Your result is exactly
>> I don't agree with them. No, but I don't
agree with the method of doing it. It's
unconstitutional. He would have been
defying the Constitution and I would
have said so, but you can't bring
yourself to say so. We've been sitting
here for several minutes. All of your
friends have seen me ask you several
times, do you agree that Donald Trump is
defining the first, fourth, fifth, 14th,
and possibly 22nd amendments? You're
you're admitted.
I understand you came in here.
>> What you are attempting to do is simply
frame this conversation like you did
with the first claim about Donald Trump.
But then when anybody asks you any kind
of question that presses you to the
least degree,
>> I answered I said I would dispense
constitution, but I would do it
constitutionally, not by executive
order. So, what I'm trying to get to is
to prove to everybody who's watching
that what you care about is not the
Constitution in what it represents or
creates. You care about the Constitution
only in so far as it allows you to
achieve your political worldview. We
agree on that. I care about the
Constitution because I don't think
presidents should be fascist dictators
and violate the Constitution. That's
what I'm saying. And he is I don't think
the president should have the power to
lock you and me up if we write an op-ed
that he doesn't like. I don't think the
president should be able to crack down
on us if you and I decide to go protest
outside his parade. I don't think the
president should be able to deprive you
and I of due process or come into our
homes without a worry. Well,
>> let's an agreement then.
>> All right, pause. You've been voted out
agreement. It's good to meet you.
>> Good to meet you, Kai.
>> Hey, how are you? I'm Eddie.
>> Hi, I'm Jessica.
>> Nice to meet you.
>> How are you? So Trump is defying the
first, fourth,
>> fifth, and 14th and maybe the 22nd soon.
>> Okay. So I want to focus on the first.
Okay.
>> And the fifth.
>> Okay.
>> So you say that Trump is defying the
first amendment. Can you give me an
example?
>> Uh for example, he banned the Associated
Press from attending White House events.
A Trump appointed judge said that was
against the First Amendment. He's been
cracking down on media organizations he
doesn't like over their speech. If they
say stuff he doesn't like, he for
example,
>> cracking down how? So for example, he
banned the Associated Press from
attending White House events because
they said it's the Gulf of Mexico.
That's not how it works. They were
already at the White House. He deprived
them for access. So he punished them for
their speech, which is why the press,
>> which is why a judge he appointed,
Trevor McFaden, said this was contrary
to the first amendment, a Trump
appointed judge. Uh he's called MSNBC
and CNN illegal. Media organizations are
not ipso, but that's free speech. He can
call them whatever they want.
>> Attacking the media
>> by the president as the executive.
>> Yeah, he can say whatever he wants.
That's that's literally the first
amendment. He can say whatever he wants.
>> Absolutely.
>> But the media can't say what they want.
>> They they do.
>> But he's going after them. He's suing
them. He's using lawsuits to crack down
on the press. President have not done
that before.
>> They used to give him 34 felonies that
Hillary Clinton did.
>> No media gave him a lawsuit.
>> No, but people on the Democratic side.
>> We're not talking about the Democrats.
>> Okay. So, he can call them whatever he
wants because that's the freedom of
speech. He can even
>> He's threatened to imprison reporters.
>> He absolutely.
>> He wants to imprison. He said reporters
should go to prison for reporting. He
threatened some of them with prison
rape. Right. That is against the first
amendment. Um, he Okay. How is that
against the First Amendment?
>> You don't think sending reporters to
prison for reporting that he doesn't
lie? Did he do that?
>> He wanted to. He said so. I would like
them to.
>> I would really like to.
>> So people other people stopped him
doesn't mean he's not defying the
Constitution. He also said if you turn
up,
>> excuse me, he can want to do something.
That doesn't mean he will or he can. And
I think he's very
>> Well, I've already given an example of
something he did do to the Associated
Press, but Okay.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, the Associated Press and
allowed in the Oval Office, which is his
office, that's his executive space.
Okay. And they are allowed in the press
room just like CNN, just like the
Guardian,
>> which he thinks are illegal media
organizations.
>> He can think he calls the media the
enemies of the people.
>> You called him a fascist.
>> Yeah,
>> you can say whatever you want.
>> But the president is I'm not the I'm not
the president of United States with the
executive power to crack down on the
media.
>> Only applies to the citizens, but not
the president.
>> I never said that. In fact, Donald Trump
runs his mouth more than anyone.
>> Absolutely he does.
>> And he doesn't just say stuff. As I
said, he actually does stuff. He
actually does crack down. For example,
you fifth amendment. Yes.
>> Due process.
>> Yes.
>> Judges have actually said you have
violated due process.
>> Yes. Except for except for people kind
of forget the Clinton the 1996
um immigration reform act where you can
you can get limited due process when you
have expedited
>> American citizens.
>> No.
>> What about American citizens?
>> Who's getting deported? That's American.
>> Two American children have been deported
multiple this year. Have you not?
>> Oh, no. No, no. Their parents have been
deported and their parents say the
father was my baby. No. Was mom legal?
>> We don't know because they didn't they
didn't go to court. And the judge I have
to go to court. That's not a part of the
due process.
>> Are you a lawyer?
>> I'm very aware of it. Are you a lawyer?
>> Do I have to be? Oh. Oh. We're making an
argument from We're making
>> It's a simple question. Are you a
lawyer?
>> Okay. We're making an argument.
>> I'll take that as a no. A Trumpappointed
judge
>> in the case, not some Marxist lefty
judge as you people like to call them. A
Trumpapp appointed conservative judge
said you cannot, it is illegal and
unconstitutional to expel or deport an
American citizen without meaningful
process. He said that in April.
>> So that was an act that Trump did. It
wasn't speech. He got rid of an American
citizen
>> from the country without process. That's
the fifth amendment violation.
>> Since I'm not up to date on that
specific, I'm sure you can.
>> So
>> well, you weren't aware that American
citizens are being deported. It's a
pretty big story. Maybe if you read the
fake news, you might know.
>> What? If you read the fake news, you
might know what's going on. A lot of
American citizens.
>> How would I know what's going on if I
read fake news? I don't watch CNN or
Rachel Matto. Sorry.
>> That's why you don't know that your
fellow citizens have been deported this
year.
>> My fellow citizens.
>> Are they not American citizens have been
deported?
>> Okay. When a child goes with their
>> All right, guys. That's time. Please
return to your seat. Nice to meet you.
>> Hey, before we go any further, we want
to take a moment to say thanks so much
to Straight Air News for powering the
fact checks in this video. Straight Air
News is on a mission to raise the bar on
journalism in a time of media bias and
mistrust. Straighter News helps you
quickly find trusted information you
need to understand the news, allowing
you to dive deep into the topics that
matter to you and the world around you.
Their work is trying to break the bias
bubble, helping you understand how every
side of the political spectrum is
reporting on a story so you get a full
picture of the news. That's why we're so
happy to be partnering with Straight
Arrow News. They deliver the facts,
unbiased, balanced, and designed to make
sense of a complex world, getting you
the clarity you deserve and news you can
trust. Go to s.com/surrounded
or click the link in the description to
check it out. By clicking that link,
you're not just supporting this channel,
you also take advantage of a better way
to get the news. Welcome back to
Trustworthy Journalism. Thanks again to
Straight Arrow News for partnering with
us on this episode. Now, let's get into
it. My next claim is that immigrants
overall are good for America.
>> Oh no, you beat me.
>> Hi, how are you?
>> Hello, nice to meet you.
>> Um, so in regards to your claim, I just
want to start by asking this. Do you
care more about helping Americans or
immigrants in this in this claim?
>> Immigrants are Americans. I'm an
immigrant and an American.
>> Well, immigrants are not Americans.
Americans are the people that were born
here.
>> That's not true. Where' you get what's
the basis of your claim for that? Are
you talking about people that get
naturalized in the process of becoming
American?
>> 14th amendment. Have you read it?
>> Okay. Yes, I have.
>> Citizenship clause. It says any persons
born or naturalized in the United States
are citizens of the United States.
>> I'm aware of that.
>> There's about 40 to 50 million
naturalized Americans in this country.
>> Yes. But
>> you didn't seem aware of it because you
said Americans versus immigrants.
>> So, but are you understanding that the
process of um getting all these
immigrants that come in here for we've
been also the millions of immigrants.
It's up to the millions. is the last 20
years now and it has dramatically
affected Americans here in the country
which
>> positively I would argue
>> people like me and everyone around here
we cannot find homes or even get jobs
within our own fields that we go to
college for that we get into debt for um
and because um more bluecollar work
especially in construction um
agriculture and so forth and the
hospitality industry we cannot get jobs
in those fields so it requires
>> are you looking for a job in
construction
>> no I went to college many people here
are in college or went to college or we
can't even find jobs in our fields also
because of the H1B visa program as well.
But in regards of just your claim about
immigrants specifically, we cannot even
get jobs to pay for housing.
>> Unemployment is at a record low right
now, even under Donald Trump, and I'm
not a Donald Trump fan, but I would say
unemployment under both Biden and Trump
has been at record low levels.
>> Okay. Is this in regards for American
citizens?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Okay. Um well, I'm unaware of that
statistic, but from what I see, u from
>> I'm an immigrant and an American, and I
employ many American citizens, both
naturalized and the ones born here. I
employ my parents. No, my parents came
Americans as defined by you.
>> My parents came as immigrants to become
naturalized. So I'm not necessarily
opposed to immigrants.
>> So you're the child of immigrants.
>> Correct. I'm a child of immigrants. I
was born.
>> But you don't accept that immigrants are
Americans.
>> Not at this moment. So your parents are
not Americans.
>> Not at this moment. Hold on. Your
parents are citizens. They became
naturalized.
>> You just said you can't be citizens by
being naturalized.
>> No, I was born here. And I'm not opposed
to naturalization. I'm against
naturalization. Are
>> your Are you against naturalization?
>> No, I never said I was against
naturalization.
>> You began You're very Everyone was here.
They can they can play it back on
YouTube. You said im Americans or
immigrants. Are your parents Americans
or immigrants?
>> No, my parents are are United States
citizens.
>> But they are immigrants. You said
>> no. They came here as immigrants.
However, behind the claim that we came I
came here as an immigrant. I'm an
immigrant at this point. When they came
the happy with the way this is going for
you.
>> The United States economy was not at um
>> it's better now. The American economy is
is better than it's been for many years.
I can say that as someone who doesn't
like Donald Trump. What statistics are
you saying?
>> Billions of dollars of minority of
minorities as well as um
>> the reason the economy is doing badly
now because Donald Trump's tariff policy
has nothing to do with migrants. In
fact, the congressional start businesses
I'm an immigrant. I started a business.
In fact, I understand because the
government is giving people billions. I
didn't take any loans. I didn't take any
loans. I'm not saying you did, but I'm
saying statistically speaking, they're
giving billions of loans.
>> So, should we do statistics? According
to statistics, immigrants are 80% more
likely to be entrepreneurs than native
born Americans are more likely to start
businesses. and hire Americans, right?
Immigrants are more likely to pay in
taxes than take out in benefits. They're
more likely to add to innovation and
jobs and wages. This is what the
statistics show. The Congressional
Budget Office, let me just finish my
point and let you come back in. The
Congressional Budget Office, which is
bipartisan, Republicans and Democrats
both use it.
>> They have said that the immigration
surge that you mentioned
>> will lead to an extra $9 trillion of GDP
over the next 10 years. That amounts to
$65,000 per American household. That's
$65,000 for each and every one of you
holding up a red flag.
>> Okay, I understand.
>> All right, pause. You've been voted out
by the majority. Please return to your
seat.
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you. Thank you.
>> Hey, how's it going? I'm Eddie.
>> What's going on, man? Nice to meet you.
All right, so first before I start, I
need to know what you mean by good. I
can talk about the economy. I can talk
about culture. I can talk about all
those things. I need to know what you
mean.
>> All of them. I'm I'm saying immigrants
are good for the economy. They're good
for wages are the econom society.
Where's the lower wages?
>> What do you mean where's the lower
wages?
>> Where are the low wages? What's the
basis for saying there are lower wages?
>> Sure. So, you can look at like the STEM
industry. It's been in like a complete
and total recession. Uh there's been
tons of studies like from the Economic
Policy Institute that shows that like uh
companies like Tesla, uh companies from
like Silicon Valley. They engaged in
mass firing of workers around 35,000,
but then they hired around 12,000 H1B
visas. And it's kind of just like just
standard economic thinking. If you
>> It's not standard economic thinking. The
vast majority of economists and economic
studies suggest that there is a
negligible if if no impact on wages over
time from immigrants. In fact, your
colleague mentioned earlier construction
there is actually evidence in
construction. Yes. But in some
industries, in some areas there is an
impact, but overall no. In fact, an a
study from the National Bureau of
Economic Research found that migrants
since 1965 have raised wages and raised
innovation. National Bureau of Economic
Research.
>> No, that No, hold on. That's where you
publish studies. I'm actually
>> I didn't memorize the names of the
authors. I know you did. Right.
>> You give me the authors. You've got
>> Yeah, hold on. The study you're talking
about is from Giovanni Perry and what he
did is he didn't account for aggregation
issues nor did he
>> the vast majority of studies
>> let me speak please yeah thank you right
so listen he didn't account for
aggregation issues right and when you
look at like the spatial approach was
what all these economists use you're not
accounting for the fact that when
immigrants come into an area natives
leave if you look at an occupational
approach where you look at look at the
specific firms that immigration's going
into like Kim ETA 2013 did you find a
net negative impact when there's a 10%
increase of immigration you find around
a.5% decline in wages when it comes to
specific occupations they're going to.
>> So all your studies are
>> so so 5% weigh that up against what I
just mentioned from the Congressional
Budget Office which is a massive boost
in GDP per head which you're not
counting for massive increase in tax
revenue. Immigrants actually funding
funding the deficits and debts by paying
way more in taxes proportionately
including undocumented. And what's
interesting about wages is I'm in a room
full of I don't know what to call you
anymore. Conservatives, Republicans,
fascists, I don't know. Uh one of you is
proudly said that correct. One of us
proudly Oh yeah, correct. I'm in a room
full of correct people, but do any of
you actually care about wages? Because
for example, do you support raising the
minimum wage?
>> Absolutely. And you can't do that when
you're bringing all these people coming
in.
>> That's not the reason the Republican
party blocks the better wage. You think
Republican politicians don't vote for an
increase in minimum wage because they're
worried about immigration Republicans?
Did I say vote Republicans?
>> Well, I'm going to show that was called
25 farright Republicans. Doesn't mean
I'm going to support every single
Republican candidate.
>> So, you and I good. So, you and I, you
and I, let's agree. We both support
raising the minimum wage. % $725 since
2009. It's lost 30% of its value. If you
care about wages, we should be raising
the minimum wage in this country. Not
scapegoating migrants who aren't the
cause of low wage in the country. You
know who's causing low wages?
Billionaires, millionaires, people who
won't pay fair wages to their wages
regardless of whether you are an
immigrant or a nation.
>> Get the monologue right now. Let me
respond.
>> You had one. You had one study that had
a.5% impact. Go.
>> Yeah. And your study like sucked that
you didn't even know who wrote it,
right? So, like let's get back to the
point because I don't need it again.
Yeah.
>> The majority of studies say that wages
are not impacted by
>> the majority of your studies are flawed.
That's what I'm telling you.
>> My studies, neither of us are
economists. It's the economist.
>> Don't assume who I am.
>> Are you economist?
>> I could be.
>> But are you?
>> Are you?
>> I'm not going to tell you.
>> Uh, I'm going to major in economics,
right?
>> Are you an economist?
>> Uh, no. Not right now.
>> Okay. So, when I said neither is
economist, I was correct to use your
favorite word.
>> See here, dude. This is nothing of
substance. Look at the red flags.
They're coming up. Let me get to the
point. So when you talk about the when
you talk about the CBO, one thing you're
not accounting for here is that they're
assuming an equilibrium, right? Do you
know what that means? You shouldn't make
these type of assumptions. You said
earlier that unemployment
>> I know what it means. I thought we were
not doing assumptions.
>> Okay, hold on. You mentioned we were
like at like 4.2 percentage
unemployment. Yeah, that's counting
people who have part-time jobs. That's
counting poverty wages. Yeah,
>> I'm against poverty wages. We agree
again.
>> Yes. If you look if you go to like the
Lwood Institute, they calculated a way
where it's like functional unemployment.
Okay. If you account for things like
just people who make around $25,000 a
year, people who have fallen out of the
labor market, people who only work
part-time, if you put if you count all
of those people together and then add on
the unemployment, that's around 25% of
the population. So when you go, we don't
have jobs. We don't have people to do
this, this, and that, and the other. No.
Yes, we do. Okay? We don't have a labor
shortage. We have a good job shortage.
And when you keep bringing these people
in and they're taking those jobs, the
good job shortage is the fault of big
firms, employees. I'm an employee. I can
say that.
>> Who hires the immigrants?
>> Who hires the immigrants? Yeah.
>> Employers.
>> Exactly. So when you bring up these big
firms, let me ask you question, right?
So let me ask you a question. If you got
rid of all immigrants coming in
tomorrow, moratorium, you think that you
think that Republicans and uh employers
of big firms would suddenly raise all
the wages. What I said, you know, it was
a complete pit of your ankles. You
pivoted the hell conversation. Is that
what you do? You believe that wages I'm
just wondering how naive you are.
believe that the 1% will raise wages and
the federal wage stop immigration. They
will be forced to when you increase
labor's relationship to capital. Okay.
And you give labor more bargaining power
because you're tightening understanding
of economics because you're explain I'm
wrong.
>> I'm tell you how you're wrong because
you're ignoring the fact that when
immigrants come into an area they spend
money. They create jobs
of their monthly income leaves.
>> They spend they that's a good thing also
because you don't like US aid foreign
aid. So this is the point. They create
jobs into this country. So far, every
one of my assumptions about you has been
correct. But listen to me. I am an
immigrant. I'm speaking from personal
experience. I don't even like
>> I should get the hell out. Why?
>> I don't want you here. Why? Cuz you come
here and say all this about how
Americans are lazy. You push your left.
>> I never said Americans are lazy.
>> I don't know why you say this.
>> You come to this country so they can do
jobs that we don't want to do. When did
I say when did I say it? YouTube. Guys
watching on YouTube, rewind to the time
where I said immigrants are doing jobs
we don't want to do. When did I say
those words? Words never came out of my
mouth.
Why do we have to bring in immigrants?
Why do we have to bring in immigrants to
the country if we have people who are
going to do the jobs?
>> Pause. Pause. You've been voted out.
>> It's nice talking to you.
>> Nice talking to you.
>> You're going to have to go.
>> You're going to have to go, bro. Is what
he said as I left to an American
citizen. Good. Good to know where you
stand on immigration. It's not about
immigration, is it? That's what it's not
about.
>> Hey, how you doing?
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Good to see you. How are you?
>> Not bad. So what type of immigrants are
we talking about?
>> What do you mean?
>> Like any immigrants or are that's why I
said immigrants
>> illegal immigrants.
>> Undocumented immigrants also contribute
greatly to the US. I I say undocumented.
I don't think people are illegal.
>> So let's put it this way. I mean I'm an
immigrant too from Iran.
>> Okay.
>> There isn't even a US.
>> How do you feel about the fact that
people here want you out?
>> Are you okay with that?
>> I'm here to debate you, not debate them.
>> I mean you're all on the same side.
You're part of one group. No,
>> you've been clapping each other. No, I
mean there are conservatives here. There
are far right people here. There are
Republicans here.
>> How do you feel about that guy wanting
me and you to leave?
>> But you know, let's I'm just wondering
this is the topic of immigration.
It's not about my feelings towards them.
>> It's about staying on this topic.
Immigrants are good for America. Yeah.
>> You and me, we're good for America
>> and the guy over there wants us to
leave. So I'm just wondering how you
feel about that.
>> So I believe that there has to be strict
immigration laws. We have to make sure
that the people are coming here have the
good intent of the United States in
mind. That's not my claim, but okay. So,
>> my claim is about immigrants are net
positive.
>> If you just open our borders to every
single person that wants to be here, you
know, that that claims that they have
economical hardship in their country.
>> Who's calling for open borders? No,
>> I'm I'm just saying, you know,
>> I mean, it's a straw man. So, you're
just saying a straw man.
>> No, I'm I'm saying
>> you're wasting time with the straw man.
No one's calling for open borders. I
didn't call for you. I said immigrants.
Who
>> you wasted time trying to cause division
between me and my
>> division? He wants you to leave the
country. That's a pretty big deal.
>> I mean, you can ignore it, but that's
your side, my Like I said, you were the
one that tried to derail this argument.
But by bringing that
>> it's to my argument. I'm saying
immigrants are good to America. People
on your side are saying we should leave.
Not me. And I asked you what type of
immigrants are we talking about? Are we
talking
>> immigrants overall?
>> Overall overall.
>> So
>> I mean you want to get into you want me
to get into like particular communities.
I'm not I'm not playing that game.
>> So you believe that people that come
here without help society without any
respect to our laws
>> and our border,
>> you know, are going to be good for this
country?
>> No, of course not. So you can't say that
all immigrants overall.
>> I never said all immigrants. I said
immigrants overall. Immigrants overall
doesn't mean all immigrants. Sorry to
break that to you.
>> All right. So So we have to make sure
that the people are coming here
>> have the good intent of this country in
mind. Agreed. I agreed.
>> Yes. Irrelevant to my claim.
>> But when you have undocumented
immigration going on, you can't vet
that. You can't make sure about that.
Let me real quick, you know, talk about,
you know, my background. There is no
Iran American embassy in Iran. So to in
order to come here, you have to stay in
line for four years and you have to go
through some some serious vetting
procedure to get here. But I made it and
that that process has to be in place
because I mean you don't want
terrorists.
>> I made it too. I'm an American citizen.
I went through lots of vetting. I took
my test
>> and that's how there wants us to leave.
>> But but
>> but he wants us to leave. So people
don't really care about vetting, do
they? It's not really about vetting, is
it, my friends?
>> People should not have the right people
should not have the right to ignore our
borders and our laws. What about those
of who don't ignore the borders? Should
we get to stay?
>> Of course. I mean,
>> and he says we shouldn't.
>> Well, I'm not debating him.
>> You We kind of You kind of are because
you're all together on this.
>> No, I'm debating you.
>> Okay. And I'm pointing out to you that
your argument is in bad faith cuz these
guys are actually speaking the truth and
you're in denial about who's on your
side. He wants you gone.
>> I I I never claim that I'm on their side
or they're on my side. I'm here to
debate you.
>> All right. Pause. You've been voted out
by the majority. Please return to Nice
to meet you.
Hey, how you doing? I'm Eddie. Edward,
nice. Nice to meet you.
>> The question is, immigration is good for
America, right?
>> Overall, if you look at the net
positives to things like our society,
our culture, our food, our economy, our
general diversity. I know the dword is a
bad word. In places like this, I think
immigrants have been a net positive. I
think if you look at your everyday
lives, we all benefit from immigration.
>> And what kind of conservatives disagree
with that?
some of the some of the guys who told me
to leave this place and go back to, you
know, not I'm not a citizen.
>> Do you think all conservatives?
>> No.
>> Oh,
>> no. In fact, Ronald Reagan, who is a
president I wasn't a big fan of until
Donald Trump came along. Now, people
like Reagan look good in comparison.
Reagan said in 1986, "Our country is a
nation of immigrants. Our immigrant
heritage is our strength." He gave an
amnesty to 3 million undocumented
migrants. He understood the value of
immigration. So, I'm with Reagan.
Although, this guy is putting his thumb
down there. So, Reagan's not popular in
right-wing crowds these days.
>> Yeah. Well, he's popular with me. good
too.
>> Uh I'm a deferred action of childhood
arrivals. I'm actually I was an illegal
immigrant myself. I came here when I was
10. I'm what you would call a legal
Elliot now. I didn't have any any say on
my parents, you know, choices.
>> Yes.
>> Do I think that they were well-meaning
by wanting to bring me over for a better
future? Absolutely. I believe that.
>> Yeah.
>> Did they break the law? Yes. Do I agree
with people breaking the law?
Not necessarily.
Do I think that there's ever a situation
where you can break the law for the
better or the greater good? You know, it
immigration is a it's an interesting
issue because I do agree with you that
>> good to hear.
>> Everyone is a an immigrant in the sense.
>> Can you tell me a little bit more about
your journey?
>> I've been here 10 years. I'm a proud
American citizen. I'm a dual national.
I'm British. I'm American. And I I am an
immigrant who's contributing to this
country. So yes, uh I'm very much proud
of America's immigrant heritage. I'm
part of it. And despite what uh one of
the other people said on this show
earlier, yeah, everyone here, unless
you're Native American, representative
of immigrants.
>> Sorry, you've been voted out. Please
return to your seat.
>> Thank you, man. Nice to meet you.
>> How's it going?
>> Hey, how's it going?
>> Actually a fan. I see you a lot on
Pierce Morgan.
>> Okay. Thank you for watching.
>> Yeah. So, um my argument so is that uh
Americans are what like what is a
nation? A nation is a geographical
location full of people who have some
things in common. So, I think some of
the things typically in history are
going to be like race, religion,
ethnicity, um language. These are some
of the things that we have to have um in
common in order to actually have a
functioning civilization, especially in
self-government. I'm not necessarily a
giant fan of self-government. I'm a
Catholic nationalist. I'm not a fascist.
You have to have at least some things in
common in order to actually have a
civilization. And the immigrants,
especially illegal immigrants that come
into this country now, uh, disrespect
us. They hate everything that we
believe. They don't even speak our
language. I watched, after Trump got
elected, I watched an interview of an
illegal alien woman crying and about
getting deported. And the entire
interview was in Spanish. That is a spit
in the face. It's disrespect. They don't
care about us. They abuse our system.
And teological argument into just a
bunch of series of wild unsubstantiated
claims asking you what is
>> I don't accept any of those claims that
they hate everything we stand for and I
don't accept well I'm not going to deal
with your tell I'm going to deal with
the false claims that you made there's
no b what's your basis for saying that
all immigrants or all undocumented
immigrants hate everything we stand for
it's funny that you said you're a
Catholic national how did most Catholics
get to America Irish Catholics Italian
Catholics immigration much of the people
coming across the southern border are
Catholics are Catholics so it's really
funny that you say you're a Catholic
But Catholics came to America via
immigration.
>> Yeah. So,
>> so immigration is good for America. You
and I can agree. Otherwise, people of
your faith wouldn't be here.
>> No. Well, we we were here on this side
of the on this side of the world in this
continent from conquest. We came over
here and
>> but the big surges of numbers as you
well know cuz you're a smart guy.
Italian Irish immigration waves,
Catholic immigration waves.
>> Okay. Yeah. And I'm not even against
those. I'm not even Were you against
those if you were alive?
>> I'm not even claiming that a lot of
people were against those.
>> I'm not claiming immigration is bad in
all cases at all times. What is your
claim?
>> My claim is that immigration especially
now and especially for foreign people
that have nothing in common with us.
>> It's funny you say it's especially now
I've forgotten your name. My apologies.
Brian in every in every era there has
been a Brian who says I'm not against
immigration. Now this is what people
said about Italians. This is what people
said about Irish folks said about
Russians Poles and now we're saying
about people coming across the southern
border because you're not being uh
you're being a little disingenuous
saying I'm only against immigrants. Now,
this is a trope disingenuous because
it's a trope that's been used by nivists
throughout American history. And every
wave of immigrants has come in and faced
the same hate and animus and bigotry and
lazy tro. And every wave of immigration
is ultimately assimilated, integrated,
benefited the country. In fact,
assimilation right now, according to
Jacob Victor from the University of
Washington, assimilation rates based on
language and citizenship and
naturalization are higher now than 100
years ago.
>> Okay, let me make a statement first. I
think that you and your own ignored my
statement you and your you and your own
person are a complete perfect example of
why immigration is negative and why we
shouldn't allow people who don't have
anything in common with us. You're pro
abortion. You're pro you euthanasia.
You're pro
>> I'm pro euthania.
>> Yeah. You went I've I've seen your
stuff. You you you've defended euthania.
>> Pro euthanasia.
>> Yeah. On Pierce Morgan.
>> No, I've never discussed euthanasia with
Pierce.
>> Okay. So my point is that you don't
agree with the guy in this country. If
anyone watching at home, I'm the only
guy here who actually supports American
values, democracy, free speech, the
Constitution. I've got folks here
telling me they don't believe in
democracy, but they're nationalist.
>> Wait, why should we why should we care
about that, by the way?
>> Isn't that what America stands for? What
does America stand for? So, you hate
what America stands for? Not me. And in
fact, all the studies show that im
immigrants actually are more patriotic.
>> The only reason Americans the only
reason the only reason why Yeah, that's
the the Mexicans in LA right now burning
it down. Waving Mexican flags being
burned down. Please don't send us back
to the country that we're waving flag.
I've been in LA for a few days. I didn't
see anything burned down.
>> Yeah, I know. The the riots have ended.
That's cuz Trump sent
>> But if it's burned down, where's it all
burned down? I haven't seen it. I've
traveled around all of LA. You said LA
was burned down. LA is 500 square miles.
It's not a fre. It's another false
burning. No, no, they're burn.
>> I support youth in Asia. LA's burned to
the ground. Immigrants hate what we
stand for. Okay. So, I'm super prot.
>> So, you're pro you're probing my
position. Immigrants are good for you.
>> You're pro abortion. You're an
immigrant.
>> I'm pro Roie Wade. Personally, I'm not
pro abortion if you knew anything about
me.
>> Uh Roie Wade is
>> all right. Pause. You've been voted out.
>> I was going to say nice to meet you,
Brian, but I guess not.
>> You made it.
>> Great to see you. My name is Cyrus.
>> Nice to meet you, Cy.
>> I am also son of two immigrants. Came in
legally. I'm also Persian descent.
Fantastic.
>> Born in LA.
>> Fantastic. Teranelis.
>> Yes. Yes. Well, I am mainly upset not at
the immigrants, legal or not. I'm mainly
upset at Wall Street. I'm mainly upset
at the elites, the special interests.
>> They are the main reason why we've been
having this issue since 1965.
>> And I most want to do well. There are a
few bad apples. We can agree, but we
want to go after the elites. They are
the main cause of the problem. And just
like healthcare, trade, everything.
>> Did you know, Cyrus, that the top 1% pay
dodge $163 billion in taxes every year,
while undocumented people pay hundred
billion in tax? So, I know where my
anger is against.
>> There there are issues with our tax
system on the rich. But in a state like
California, some taxes are too high. I
used to live here now in Las Vegas.
>> Different debate. I'm saying immigration
is good for America. People like you and
me overall are good for America is what
I'm saying.
>> Okay. But it depends on how it's done.
>> Yes.
>> It depends on how it's done. how it's
being done to the US.
>> I'm not blaming the housing crisis on
immigrants, not on wages. But in a state
like California that doesn't build
enough homes and they're bringing
immigrants in, you have to increase
supply of housing. Okay? But this is
where our anger is at is at the
political class. The Democrat party used
to have a different stance on
immigration 15 years ago. Bernie
Sanders, Hillary Clinton.
>> I'm not a fan of I'm not here to defend
different Democrats. What I will say is
our angle.
>> What I will say is that everyone here
actually does think immigration is good
for America. Everyone here uses an
iPhone designed by an immigrant is on
Gmail designed by an immigrant is uh
watch is on a YouTube show. We all came
to a YouTube show founded by an
immigrant. You wouldn't but that's a
tiny minority.
>> So you all love immigrants whether you
like it or not.
>> Okay. But it's a taboo subject. Should
we be concerned about the demographic?
So no
>> Anglo-Saxon European-American 0% of
America. It doesn't matter. Are they 0%
of America?
>> Well, let's say if it becomes 0%. It
should not work.
>> They're not going. Why are you bringing
weird hypotheticals?
>> Well, but there has But I mean, they're
still part of our country. There's
culture. There's I mean, even Britain
like concerns, but it concerns me when
Britain is changing and it's, you know,
it's like they're losing their culture,
but it's losing their culture. Are they?
Are they going to try to
>> UK? I'm telling you, no one's losing
their culture.
>> London is going to be very little
British in one day.
>> What's the plan? That's what we want to
know. What's the plan?
>> You just made that up. Have you been to
London? How do we know?
>> Cyrus, have you been to London?
>> So then maybe you shouldn't come on
places you don't know anything about.
>> But what's the plan?
>> I grew up in London. London is a very
British city. I was in London a few
weeks ago. It's a very British city.
>> I hope not. I understand that there are
people in this audience that don't like
me or you in this country and I respect
that. There's some that don't even want
me to date a blonde woman. They want to
keep to their own or ginger or whatever.
I respect that. But there has to be a
deal made. There's Idaho. There's
Montana. they can go live in a
homogeneous society. I don't believe in
force. Okay? And I believe that there
has to be a deal made and I think
there's upsides and downsides to
diversity.
>> There's a deal made. People have
elections. They vote for elections. And
right now there's Donald Trump in the
White House. Not someone I support, but
people voted for him.
>> Well, why did he get in? Mainly because
I'm not sure we have time. 2016.
Okay.
>> Part of the reason he got in is that
people in this room want people like me
and you to leave and they voted for him
to try and make that happen.
>> I'm not surprised. One of the
Charlottesville marchers doesn't like me
and I've met those people and I respect
their views.
>> You really shouldn't.
>> Well, their wants.
>> Don't respect racists and fascists is my
advice to you.
>> Well, they have their preferences. You
know, that's just we can't change that.
>> Actually, we can. Why I tried to come in
today, but anyways.
>> All right, that's time. Please return to
your seat.
>> Thank you. Nice to meet you.
>> Pleasure. Good.
My final claim is that Donald Trump's
plan for Gaza is ethnic cleansing.
>> Hey Sarah, nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you.
>> You too. So why why do you say this is
Donald Trump's plan? Why do you think
that?
>> I mean, he says it's his plan.
>> Have you seen his plan?
>> When did he say it?
>> He said it standing next to Benjamin
Netanyahu in January, February. He said
it on Fox News in an interview uh on
Fox. He said it on Air Force One when he
was chatting to reporters.
>> Word like word for word. What's an
example of what he said?
>> Uh word for word, he said, for example,
we're going to clean out the Gaza Strip.
He said they're going to leave. We're
going to take control of it. He says,
uh, we'll own it. I would own it. He
says, I'm not sure under international
law how he can own a foreign piece of
land. And when he was asked on Fox News,
uh, the people, the Palestinians who are
being forced to leave, would they be
able to come back? He said, no, they
wouldn't. That is the literal definition
of ethnic cleansing according to a UN
definition.
>> Do you think that Trump is saying this?
Do you think that he has some personal
interest in cleansing Gazar? Do you
think there might be some special
interest group or perhaps religious or
ethnic group that's you know that maybe
he received money from them and that's
the whole reason why uh he wants to
cleanse Gazer. Why do you think that is?
>> I don't do Donald Trump's motivations. I
really don't care. My claim is that what
he's doing is ethnic cleansing. Do you
agree with that?
>> I would actually yeah probably agree.
But I'm just
>> You agree that it's ethnic cleansing.
You agree with doing ethnic cleansing?
>> No, I don't agree with it. But I agree
that's probably his plan. But I'm trying
to figure out like why do you think that
is? Because Donald Trump's a white man.
He identifies as Christian. I'm not sure
if he really is. But what interest does
he have in preserving a Jewish
ethnostate? Like why would he have that?
>> It's a good question. You'd have to ask
Donald Trump that question. I've got
multiple views. I'm sure you have many
views. I'm I'm not sure I like where
you're going with your views, but um I
think Donald Trump is definitely someone
who's got financial interests in ethnic
cleansing. He's got political interests.
He loves the evangelical vote. He get a
lot of Christian evangelicals like to
support Israel because they think Jesus
will come back if all the Jews are
gathered in one place with no
Palestinians. Uh I think he's going to
make money he thinks from beachfront
property with Jared Kushner. Uh he said
something similar in the past.
>> You think that's the real reason?
>> I think there's multiple reasons. Yeah.
I think financial, geopolitical,
ideological, evangelical. I don't really
care. My claim is that what he's doing
is ethnic cleansing. Ethnic cleansing is
a war crime according to the fourth
Geneva Convention. It's against
international law under the Rome
Statute. So we shouldn't be part of
that. The United States should not be
supporting Donald Trump's plan for
ethnic cleansing. I agree. Uh what do
you think what do you think should be
done instead uh to with the Israel Gaza
situation? I'm not sure what your
>> state would like to see a ceasefire in
Gaza. I would like to see I don't really
get into debates about what solutions. I
would like to see an end to the killing.
I would like to see Gazans have freedom.
I would like to see the Palestinians in
Gaza somehow get their land back. 80% of
Gaza right now is under Israeli military
control or displacement. I would like to
see freedom for the Palestinian people.
I'm an American. To go back to the core
of this show, I spot American values.
One person, one person free speech. It
really is a religious and ethnic battle.
>> A religious battle.
>> Well, yes. That is what it's obviously
between Jews and Muslims want control of
the holy land.
>> No, it's not.
>> Yes, it is. What else? What other
>> actually the founders of Israel were
secular. They were not religious
actually. And I think some religious
Jews like Bazalot who's minister. It
doesn't really matter. Is a religious
fanatic. But no, the core of the
conflict is over land. It's colonial.
>> It's historic. It is not about religion.
>> Colonialism is for a reason. steal the
land, want everyone to believe it's
religious.
>> My point is, why are we sitting here?
Why are we sitting here? It's like a a
false dichotomy where we have to argue
like, do Jews get Israel? Do Muslims get
Israel? Why are like we never brought up
anyone's religion? How many of us bring
up anyone's religion? How many of us
here are Christians? I didn't bring up
anyone's relig trying to pick sides
between Jews and Muslims taking over
Israel. Like, don't you think that
>> Hold Hold up. First of all, I didn't
bring up religion. Second of all, you
know that a lot of Palestinians are
Christian, right?
>> Some of them.
>> You're just reducing it to Muslim versus
it's majority Muslim. Yeah, it's very
>> But there are many prominent parties. I
>> agree. Yeah, but there's not that many.
>> It's not worth everything.
>> Well, it is the reason. Why do you think
Iran is backing proxies that want to
take over Gaza, you know, back the
terrorism Gaza? It's obviously because
they want to Muslim control of the land.
You don't think that's why?
>> No, I don't think it's about religion.
>> Is it?
>> I' I've been following this conflict for
decades. It's not about religion. People
who say it's about religion, it's a
distraction.
>> Well, it's a big part of it. I think
>> I think it's become a big part of it.
It's been weaponized by bad faith
actors. Sure, but I don't think that's
the core. The core is that one people,
one group of people are dominating
another group of people.
>> What group of people is it? But what
group of people is dominating another
group of people?
>> One ethnic group is dominating another
ethnic group. What ethnic group?
>> Jewish people.
>> Yes. Dominating
>> Arabs.
>> Yes.
>> But I didn't say anything about
Christian, Muslim, Jew in a religious
sense.
>> Jews define as religion and ethnic. Do
you know that? Right.
>> Well, why why do you think that Muslims
want control of the Holy Muslims? I
didn't bring up Muslims.
>> Well, they're Muslim states. Like what
do you think like Iran wants to do with
Bran? But but that's part of the
conversation. What do you mean?
>> No, it's not. The conversation is Donald
Trump is doing ethnic cleansing and you
agree with me. So I'm not sure why
you're still here.
>> It's part of the larger contest.
>> It's a weird debate when you actually
agree with me.
>> What I was trying to say is we kind of
have this false dichotomy here where
we're trying to take the you know the
side of the gauins which mostly it's a
Muslim majority or the side of human
beings who are suffering human beings.
You should try who gets control over
Israel.
>> I say about control. America is a
majority Christian country. Should we be
deciding Christians should have control
of
>> I agree. Donald Trump should not nothing
to do with religion. Donald Trump should
not be deciding what happens to Gaza.
That's my claim. If you agree with me,
great. Let's shake hands. Give the seat
to someone who disag. Do you think that
America should just cut ties with Israel
altogether?
>> What's your definition of cut ties?
>> Like stop funding them, stop being a
military arm.
>> Yes, I'm on record saying that was an
easier debate.
>> Whoa. Welcome back, Richie. you really
want to be here.
>> Um, first of all, I I really thought
that obviously where we started, where
it ended up, there's a lot of
aggression. I can see in your eyes
there's a level of exhaustion from being
here. This is where my empathy comes in.
Where it doesn't is, you know, when you
have a room full of people that do agree
with you, we have this opportunity to
come together and you're kind of mocking
people when they do. So, you mock Sarah
a little bit when you guys clearly had a
common interest and goal to reach. So, I
can tell you're agitated. I want to
bring that all down. Please,
>> I'm I'm guessing you're not going to,
but let's see.
>> No, no, I'm going to. I do want to point
out some contradictions. First and
foremost, I don't believe you're
pro-American in the value system that
you claim to uphold, especially with
free speech if you're not willing to
debate people that don't share your
values. That's very un Trump's plan for
Gaza is ethnic cleansing.
>> I I don't believe it's ethnic cleansing,
but I but I cuz it's not his plan.
>> It is his plan. He said it's my plan.
>> No, he's not call his plan.
>> He is obeying someone else's plan.
>> Okay.
>> Who is he obeying? Uh he is obeying
Israel's plan. Okay. Uh for the greater
Israel project of which this is one of
those things that we can agree on. We're
not Why is he doing that? I don't I
don't know. Maybe they have something on
him. Maybe they have something on all of
you think it's a bad thing what he's
doing.
>> Absolutely. Okay.
But see, you're I don't want to shut
down agree with you. Okay, perfect. You
know, but I I I want to take this
opportunity because I don't know if I'm
going to get the opportunity again to
say you're not American first and
foremost. You're not
>> Remember what I said? The agitation from
you is not going to be there. But what
I'm saying,
>> you came to lower the temperature and
then make racist remarks. You know
that's a racist remark.
>> It's not racist.
>> You tell an American citizen.
>> But okay, perfect. Perfect. You just
proved your own point. You just said
that was a racist position. Earlier you
you argue this contention that America
has no race. It's a bunch of immigrants
that culminate together.
>> America has no race.
>> You you inferred it. You absolutely did.
So now you're saying it's racist for me
to take American nationalist approach.
You're kind of
>> American national approach. Is that a
white approach? I I think it's a a white
nivist approach of of course only
Americans are white people. Why did your
parents immigrate only white people?
>> Why did your parents immigrate from
India to the UK?
>> Because the UK colonized and conquered
India.
>> Okay. Why did you immigrate to America?
>> Because many reasons.
>> Okay. All opportunity. There's
opportunity.
>> You don't know
>> the accent. Your accent is a is an
afflect of of white Anglo-Saxon.
>> You know there are 50 million Americans
in this country.
>> I understand. But you're
>> none of them are Americans in your view.
what I'm trying to get you to do to
reach a common ground here.
>> We're not gonna reach a common ground
because you said I'm not American.
>> Please try.
>> I don't think you're American.
>> I'm saying I'm saying you're not
American. I'm not I'm saying you're not
American due to values.
>> I don't think you're not American on
values either. I think you're a little
fascisty, a little racist.
>> See, you're using these words. Okay.
First of all, I want to say this. I'm
not just throwing you sit down. I said
every conservative that has ever been
shut down by leftists like you. For
every conservative, for every
conservative, you've already said, for
every rightwing, for every Stefan Mu Mu,
Thomas, Nick Fuentes, all of those
people American.
>> He's Australian. But but but that's the
point. I'm saying people that are on our
side of the aisle that get shut down by
people like you because you're
leveraging this position of emotion.
You're joking, right? No, I'm not.
You're leveraging
my side of the aisle is trying to deport
you.
>> The only shut down they're actually
trying my entire race. So, what are you
talking about?
>> What are you talking about?
>> You're a white genocide guy.
>> Are you kidding me? You know the fact
you're
>> I'm amazed that Jubilee find some of you
guys. How do they find you?
>> Do you email you?
>> Do you have
>> Why are you trying to ou me?
>> Do you go to Nordstrom? All immigrants.
Have you ever been on eBay? Immigrants.
You love immigrants.
>> You love immigrants when they're helping
you. You just don't like the color of my
skin.
>> We're having a different genocide.
>> All right. You've been voted out. Please
return to your seat. Okay. I really wish
we could have got
>> I mean, you believe in white genocide,
so it's very hard to
>> Hello.
>> Hey, how's it going?
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Hello. So, um, I'll switch over to the
Gaza thing in a second, but first off, I
just wanted to touch on that. You said
that you support free speech, of course,
right?
>> So, what I'm confused about is you've
refused to debate people that I've
disagreed with you because you said that
they're racist or they're fascist,
right?
>> No, no, no, If we're going to do facts,
they said they were racist and fascist.
Get your facts right before you start
arguing.
>> So, isn't the whole entire point of a
debate to debate people that you don't
agree with? I don't debate people who
don't see me a as equal. No point. Or b
support democracy because that would
undermine the whole idea of the debate.
If you don't support democracy as our
friend here doesn't, and support General
Franco, then what is the point of a
debate? The first amendment doesn't mean
you have to debate everyone. Somebody
comes up to you in the street and starts
talking to you, you don't you don't have
an obligation to carry on talking to
them. I'm sure you go about your
business. somebody comes up to you in
the subway and sits next to you and
starts ranting in your face, you're not
going to start debating. Everyone here
has hygiene standards as do you. There
are people you wouldn't debate, I'm
sure, as well.
>> Okay. So, can you please uh describe why
you think Trump is uh supporting ethnic
cleansing of GSA just because he wants
to take over the land there? How does
that kill?
>> Not just take over the land,
>> kick out all the people. That is the
definition of ethnic cleansing.
>> So, isn't ethnic cleansing killing
people? Because it seems like you're
>> No, you can ethnic cleanse people
without killing them. And by the way,
they have been killed. More than 50,000
people in Gaza have been killed by the
Israelis, by people like Bazalmotrich
who said recently the finance minister
of Israel, "We are going to Gaza to
conquer, cleanse, and remain. We are
going to annihilate the place. We're
going to disassemble Gaza." He said,
"We're going to leave it behind as piles
of rubble. That's the guy Trump's
funding, supporting, that's the guy
praising Trump." So yes, Trump and
Smootrich are ethnically cleansing.
>> I can I cannot deny I cannot deny that
thousands of people are dying in Gaza.
But you need to realize why are they
dying? Is it possibly that they're
attacking another country because people
are dying attacking another country?
Just because Israel is killing more
Gazins than Gazins are killing Israel
doesn't mean Gaza is righteous and
Israel is evil.
>> I never said anything about evil or
right. I said ethnic cleansing. You said
don't they have to be killed? I said
they are being killed and the criteria
for what's happening to them. If Donald
Trump says these people have to leave
and never come back, is that not ethnic
cleansing? What is your definition of
ethnic cleansing?
>> I would think ethnic cleansing is when
you're killing off a uh large part of an
ethnic group.
>> That's genocide. You're confusing your
terms. Ethnic cleansing is removing one
ethnic group
>> using a deliberate policy by violence or
terror inspiring means to remove another
population, another ethnic group from a
certain geographic area. That's the UN
definition of ethnic cleansing. That is
what he's doing. When he was asked
Donald Trump, can they come back? He
said no, they cannot. That is I think
I've heard all these fact people talk
about white genocide today. You guys are
nationalists. How would you feel if
somebody came the president of France
came and told you to leave your land and
not come back? Would you not feel you'd
been ethnically cleansed from your home?
>> From America?
>> Yeah. Well, because I'm a I'm my my
ancestors were settlers here, not
immigrants. They actually
>> Palestinians are not immigrants in Gaza.
>> They are indigenous people to the land.
>> Didn't Israel just give Gaza the land
like a few decades ago?
>> No.
>> I'm pretty sure Israel used to have that
land.
>> I'm pretty sure you're wrong. They
withdrew from 2005 from the land, but
control the air
>> them in 2005.
>> No, they don't give it to them. They
control the air, the sea space, the
borders, the population registry. They
controlled what went in and out. It was
a prison, an open air prison. That's not
giving them.
>> Don't they have a border with Egypt and
then the Mediterranean
>> and Israelis and Egyptians work together
because Donald Trump and Joe Biden and
Barack Obama?
>> Yes, they're funded by the United
States. Did you know that Muslim
countries do bad things, too?
>> No, I know that do they do bad things.
>> Okay, then we're in agreement.
>> All right, pause. You've been voted out.
Please return to your seat. Nice
>> to meet you.
>> No one. Great.
>> Hello, sir. Welcome back.
>> See you again, Miy. All right. So, I
agree that Trump wants to do a
cleansing,
but not an ethnic one because that area
requires a lot of cleansing because when
you have a population that was taught
from early childhood age to hate Jews,
Christians, and pagans, you need some
serious re-education.
>> Number one, that's not true. And number
two, that's not what he's proposing.
>> Well, I mean, mo most Palestinians by
polling number do support Hamas.
>> They support resisting Israel. Well, I
mean the thing is, you know, what did
they do in the first place that they are
in this uh what you call open air
prison?
>> Great question. What did they do to
deserve being occupied?
>> Well, here's the thing. Because the
Islamic Republic in Iran is using them
as a tool.
>> What does this as a tool for their
Islamic expansion?
>> When did the Islamic Hold on. When did
the Islamic Republic of Iran You're
Iranian American, I believe?
>> Yes, I am.
>> When was the Islamic Republic of Iran
founded?
>> 1979.
>> When was Gaza occupied by Israel?
uh 19 well the very first 67 yeah so can
we do the maths together 12 years before
the Islamic Republic of Iran existed
Israel was oppressing occupying
dispossessing the people of Gaza so your
argument makes no sense
>> were there any terrorist organizations
at the time
>> the PLO was considered a terrorist
organization by the entire western world
>> all right so was Hamas there
>> Hamas did not exist till the 1980s
>> exactly my point is after the Islamic
Republic came it became chaotic because
the Islamic Republic started to lose the
what the so-called innocent Palestinians
for their own
>> so-called innocent Palestinian. You
don't think Palestinians are innocent?
>> Not all of them because
>> what about the 17,000 children who were
killed?
>> They're doing the same.
>> 17,000 children were killed. Were they
not innocent?
>> Who uh were they not innocent?
>> Who's responsible for that?
>> Israel dropped the bomb.
>> Hamas is responsible. Hamas is
responsible for hiding in hospitals and
and banking tunnels underneath.
>> So when children are shot in the head by
Israeli snipers, Israeli snipers aren't
responsible for that.
>> Look, it's a simple question. Here's the
problem. When Israeli snipers shoot
Palestinian children in Gaza in the
head, as eyewitness testimony and
doctor's testimony proves, that's not
the fault of the Israeli snipers.
>> This is this is the problem because then
you have a problem.
>> The problem is you won't answer the
question. I'll ask you a third time.
When Israeli snipers shoot Palestinian
children in the head, is that not the
fault of Israeli snipers?
>> Well, you got to let me finish.
>> No, you got to answer the question
fourth time. When Israeli snipers
Palestinian children in the head, we're
running out of time. I need to know what
you think about innocent children cuz
what you said was pretty outrageous. You
said so. innocent Palestinians for the
fifth time when Palestinian children are
shot in the head by Israeli snipers. Is
that not the fault of Israel?
>> What did those children do?
>> What did you tell me? Did the children
deserve to be shot in the head? Because
the problem is millions of people are
watching you say
children. They start brainwashing
children at a at a very long young age.
>> So you support sniping children in Gaza?
Do other people here support sniping
children in Gaza? Is that a conservative
position now?
>> What if they're wearing a suicide vest?
>> They weren't. But what if they are?
>> They're not though. Dozens of children.
I have friends who went there. Doctors
went to American doctors. They came back
and we have multiple children.
What if they're hellbent on killing you
and your family?
>> A 10-year-old child, an 8-year-old
child, a six-y old child.
>> Because because you sitting on
television where millions of people are
going to see, your neighbors, your
friends, you support the killing of
children. Millions of people don't know
what's going on.
>> Even your fellow rightwingers are
saying, "Don't go this far.
genocide. Sure. But don't
>> millions of people don't understand the
brainwashing that is going on in Isra
Islamic Republic and in Palestine to
create this obsessed with Iran so much
that you're supporting the killing of
Palestinian children who never harmed
you or any other Israeli. That's insane.
Look,
>> and the fact that you support Trump's
ethnic cleansing now doesn't surprise
me.
>> I didn't say ethnic cleansing. I said
cleansing of the land because you need
to cleanse the land from
said you've been voted out. Please
return to your seat.
How you doing? Good to see you again.
>> I'm good. I'm good seeing you, too, man.
>> Uh, first thing I'm going to say is, uh,
I'm not dying for Israel. Okay, that's
the first thing I'm going to say. And,
uh, I don't like when you come up here
and you use the type of rhetoric that
you do. You talk like all these like
leftwing positions and then you go to
the last part, which is I don't support
ethnic cleansing in Palestine. I think
you're doing a huge disservice to pro
Palestinians when you start allowing
aligning yourself with all these
progressives. Um I I don't think it
looks good because you have all these
conservatives in here who oppose war.
They oppose intervention in the same
tradition of Pat Buchanan and all the
greats that came
>> about Donald Trump though sadly.
>> Yeah, it is sad. It is sad. I do agree.
I mean he ran on an anti-war ticket. He
said he was gonna I didn't
>> because he lies, right?
>> You gonna let me talk or you just want
to Yeah, true. So I mean yeah you keep
you know you keep going back to Trump. I
don't think this is part of his plan. I
think this is a plan of lobbyists and
this is not just unique to Trump. It's
been a thing since the Democrats. It's
been a thing since the Republicans
before him. It's it's been like this
since Truman. I don't know if you read
like John Mirshimer's the Israel lobby
or anything like that. Would you agree
or disagree with anything like that?
>> Oh, I agree with Steven John Mesh. Yeah,
for sure.
>> Okay, great. So, I'm just wondering when
you ally yourself with all these
leftists and you come up here and you
argue for immigration, you argue up here
that, you know, Trump's this bad
criminal and this and that and then you
>> think Trump's bad too. a bad I think
he's good on some questions and bad on
other things. But let me get to my point
here is you allow yourselves with guys
like uh you know Jewish Voices for Peace
and all those guys.
>> Great people.
>> Yeah. Not really though. Why?
>> Cuz they're self-interested in it. It
says by definition it says it says it on
their home page.
>> By definition they're not
self-interested, right? They're going
against their own.
>> Are you going to let me talk? On their
homepage it literally says that we are
here to segregate Judaism from Zionism.
It's very clear they're doing this in
their own interest. That's why it
literally says Jewish voices for peace.
They're going to be the good Jews who
say that we don't support Palestine. And
then what happens is you take all these
progressives, you go out there and LAR
in the street. Then everyone here who's
conservative, they're going to broke for
the pro-war candidate because they don't
want to be associated with all the
liberals.
>> You're forced to vote for pro-war
people. Poor people.
>> It's either that or get replaced in my
country. What do you want me to do?
>> Oh, you and your replacement
>> Yeah. Okay, buddy.
[Applause]
>> Oh wow, there's three people so far.
Let's keep counting. We should be nicer
to you, otherwise you'll deport us. What
a great argument. This is the free
speech debate.
>> It's not your country, my friend. It's
our country whether you like it or not.
>> I I thought Kai was he smiled. He
laughed. He disagreed. He did it. I felt
like it was good faith. Let's see.
>> I appreciate it, Eddie.
>> He seemed to be in good faith. He seems
kind of smart and uh you know he's one
of the few people who doesn't want to
deport me or or maybe not. We're going
to find out.
>> My claim is we should get rid of
birthright citizenship.
>> Why do you want to get rid of birthright
citizenship and how by the way? Because
you know it's in the constitution. I'm
so glad you brought this up. Yes.
Because it was one of my
>> the 14th
>> 14th I mentioned it to a bunch of your
friends and nobody wanted to engage in
the 14th. Let's talk about the 14th
amendment citizenship clause which says
>> that if you're born here you're a
citizen of the United States.
>> Yes. I well I and I chose this because
it's an it's an extension of the
original debate and the immigration
debate.
>> Okay.
>> I think birthright citizenship first of
all when it was originally argued um you
know among the the people who were who
are actually voting on the clause right
it was argued that the birthright
citizenship was not automatically
extended to everybody who was just born
here. And we have a long history of that
as well for example with the Native
Americans who had particular laws that
applied solely to them. What I think
we're seeing in this country is not
everybody is so similarly under the
jurisdiction thereof of the United
States, right? And by allowing for
birthright citizenship and not
interpreting the Constitution as we're
legally allowed to and restrict, you
know, the automatic citizenship of
anybody who's born here, we actually
remove the issue, for example, of family
separation because there is no incentive
of a family to come over to this country
illegally and then have a child, which
is contributing to the awful situation
we have in America of breaking up
families. This is not something that I
imagine you or I agree with.
>> No,
>> the issue is birthright citizenship
hasn't incentivized that.
>> So even if I were to concede that in
some cases birthright citizenship has
incentivized that that you know I don't
like the phrase anchor babies, but I'm
not naive enough to pretend that there
are not immigrants who come here and
time the pregnancy in order to get
>> of you can you and I can agree on that.
>> Yeah.
>> But that doesn't mean you then rip up a
constitutional principle that goes back
centuries. Goes back before the 14th
amendment. 14th amendment came about I
think in 1868 if memory serves me
correctly
>> but the principle underlying it is
actually from my other country the UK
ancient English common law right so this
was always the case the 14th amendment
as you know because you seem well read
came along and codified what was already
a principle in American and English law
that if you're born in the country you
are a citizen now you mentioned the
point about jurisdiction there is that
little bit in there in where it says
subject to the jurisdiction thereof that
in the debate if you go back and read
the debate that the senators had at the
time they were very explicit that that
was to do with foreign ministers and
foreign ambassadors, diplomats living in
embassies decades shouldn't be citizens.
Obviously, they're here on their own.
You know, the the Argentine embassy in
DC, it's Argentine soil, you know. So,
we accept all that. Absolutely. But when
they were asked but when they were asked
about Chinese immigrants, Senator
Trumbull, who was uh I think the chair
of the judiciary committee back in the
1860s during this debate,
>> he said at the time, Chinese immigrants
children, they are citizens. In fact,
1898, as you well know, we get Wong Kim
Arc, Supreme Court case, Wongqim Arc
versus the United States, and the
Supreme Court says yes, even the child
of undocumented Chinese immigrants is an
American citizen. So, this is a
principle going back centuries. So,
while I can agree with you that there
are cases that abuse the 14th amendment,
that there are issues of family
separation, I'm not going to rip up a
constitutional principle that goes back
centuries and is backed by what 27y old
Supreme Court president because Donald
Trump is looking for ways to cut the
number of brown and black people in the
United States.
>> If if you don't mind me interrupting,
this is this is where I think it's
important as well to go back to what we
talked about with the Constitution. When
we're analyzing, and I admittedly, I'm
not as interested in the legal argument.
There's obviously many ways to interpret
the constitution. Y, but I don't think,
especially among conservatives, that it
is positive to use the constitution to
dismantle it. When we analyze the
original context, like you were saying
in in the late 19th century, our
immigration law was absolutely
different. Including, you know, in
respect with the Irish and Chinese
immigrants that were coming over, it was
absolutely different. Chang,
>> we had open borders, my friend. Some
people in this room would hate it. We
had open borders for half of American
history.
>> Well, that I don't think that's very
that's very that's very true. It's 100%
true.
>> Well, hold on. If you're comparing the
open borders, which I don't concede to,
but if you're comparing the open borders
prior to like 1910 and prior to the
heart seller act and you look at the
amount of immigration and who was coming
over,
>> nice deflection amount is irrelevant. We
did have an open absolutely relevant
because the constitution like the
founding father your argument is we had
open borders fewer immigrants.
>> I was about to answer.
>> It's important to analyze the context
wherein these laws and parts of the
constitution arise. The original
founding fathers said the constitution
was made only for immoral and religious
people and is wholly inadequate to the
government of any other. Which means the
people that wrote this document
understood that it would not be able to
properly
>> super secular people. Let's just be
clear on that.
>> Well, no, that's not true. They were
deist.
>> No, the majority were deists.
>> But they were secular. Secular doesn't
mean atheist. You know what I mean?
>> I understand that. But theist doesn't
mean secular or atheist. It means they
believe in a god but not a god. That's
about
>> whether they're theist or theist. I said
they're secular. But secular means you
separate church and state.
>> Okay. Well, let's talk. We could even
talk about that. That's a perfect
example.
>> You're going to run out of your own time
making your argument which I haven't
made so far.
>> I understand. But the separation of
church and state is now completely
differently understood than originally
proposed. Thomas Jefferson who talks
about the wall of separation which
doesn't even exist in the constitution
understood it as a Supreme Court
president as you well know.
>> Yeah. Sure. But the president of the
last 100 years where in the country has
been completely different from its
founding should not overrule the
original intent of the people who wrote
the document that you and I are both
citing. Okay.
>> Which means
>> but I don't but I'm not I'm not locked
into what the people who write. We've
had amendments to the constitution. You
know that right?
>> I understand that. And this is our
fundamental disagreement is that I I
don't believe
>> you think you can read the minds of
people in the 1770s. That's not true.
And and I'm stuck.
>> I just I just believe this country ought
to be more like the country we
originally had. And I don't think
>> that's your opinion. You're entitled to
I understand that.
>> But they're a factual basis.
>> Well, let me let me try to see what you
believe.
>> Okay.
>> If we are voting on these constitutional
amendments, if we are interpreting them
and our interpretation becomes
absolutely let's say a 180 from what the
original intent of the authors of that
document is,
>> are you in favor of that?
I guess depends on the issue.
>> Okay. I would say no matter what.
>> So for example, take the second
amendment which we kind of danced
around. It's not been but come up here
and there. You know the debate about the
second amendment is the fundamental
debate is one side says it's it's
limited and the other side said no no
what they meant was the militias. They
didn't and they and they had musketss.
They didn't mean AR-15s, right? So we
could have that endless debate which I
really don't care for about that. But to
come back to your point about the
constitutional principles, the 14th
amendment comes along in the 1860s. It's
pretty old. It's not as old as America,
but it comes along and it's been around
for 150 years. So if you want to get
away, it was around before 150 million
Americans.
>> And I'm saying it was around before the
United States was even created. It's
part of ancient English common law. If
you're born in a place, you're a citizen
of that place, unless you're a child of
a foreign diplomat or on a Native
American reservation.
>> English English common law did not exist
simultaneously as millions of people
coming across the border in a year.
>> Just to get to principles, your argument
is numbers change everything because
we've got so many more people. Not
solely, but absolutely. Okay.
>> The demog the demographics of your
immigration.
>> Can I ask you a question? If you got rid
of if you got rid of the 14th amendment,
>> what would be in its place?
>> I think a citizenship test would be
fantastic. I wish um I think we could
administer it in high school
>> to everyone or just the immigrants.
>> No, everybody.
>> And then if you fail it, you do you
denaturalize white American people?
>> Maybe you can't get a government job.
>> That dude,
>> I I think there's plenty of benefits
that the government offers people that
you should not be uh able to to receive.
>> I'll tell you this, right? I I this is
this might sound bad and I think
>> I don't think you people care for me
anyway. So let me say something you
might not like.
>> Nobody would pass it.
>> If you have a high school immigration
citizenship test for everyone
>> I think people will take citizenship
more serious.
>> The immigrant kids are going to
outperform the white kids and you might
actually end up denaturalizing some of
the white kids and then people here will
be really upset
>> and well hold on and and I like to be
consistent about this. That's possible.
But what I think it would do is it would
give everybody a larger sense of the
importance of citizenship.
>> So you would say no one born in this
country is a citizen. No one would
>> automatically no. Automatically no. I
think I think we could extend that. You
know, people who have a heritage in the
country.
>> Where are they until they pass the test?
>> Undocumented,
>> I suppose. Yeah. They they are not able
to receive government benefits. They're
not able to receive government benefits.
They're not able to apply for these jobs
that
>> are citizens.
>> Okay. Well, hold on. This we're talking
here about the way that we would
implement it. I'm
>> pretty important. If you're trying to
get rid of the 14th amendment, I'm going
to ask about the practicalities of it
>> and Trump's doing it right.
>> Hold on. And I'm not going to be able to
explain it to you in 10 minutes. But
what I can explain to you is that right
now in this country, we have a crisis of
people not Hold on. We're not
understanding what citizenship is. The
way that you've referred to citizenship
makes everybody who hasn't come to the
United States an undocumented American
citizen until the time they come over
here.
>> That's how a lot of countries are,
right? You know that you know that
birthight citizenship is operated by
multiple n democracies around the world.
I know Trump lies and says we're the
only country that does it. He lies.
That's not true. Multiple countries.
>> You think it ought to be that way? Do
you think everybody in the world is an
undocumented American?
>> Hold on. Well, or undocumented Canadian
or undocumented Brit, right? Or
undocumented.
>> Sure. Well, I'm an American, so I say
America. But yeah,
>> but I'm saying, right, the principle is
you immigrate. We have free movement
people. I support free movement of
people around the world.
>> But do you believe they're all
>> Are you Kim Jong-un? You think people
should only stay in one country and
never leave and be blocked from leaving
their country? That's a very illiberal
and conservative position.
>> I think there's a big libertarian big
there's big room to move between being
Kim Jong-un and saying that
>> in practical terms if you I gave one
side. I want to give the other. There's
a big room to move between being Kim
Jong-un and saying that everybody in the
world is an American. They're just not
on our soil yet. I think being an
American that's a ridiculous statement,
right? Because everyone in the world is
not heading to the United States of
America. Yeah. In fact, right now
numbers of people coming in and
dropping.
>> But the idea that you are supporting is
that the moment you come to this soil
>> and that you're born here, you become an
American. And I
>> So I'm not saying the moment you come to
this soil, you become an American. I
didn't. I had to do the test, right? I
had to do the naturalization process
which is guaranteed by the 14th
amendment. But the 14th amendment also
says if you're born here then you
automatically get it. And I'm not saying
I think the problem is a hill I'm gonna
die on.
>> The problem we have
instead we don't appreciate citizenship.
The problem is that when you talk about
immigration like we did before when we
talked about everything before what were
we talking about? We were talking about
products. We weren't talking about
practices or perceptions which is really
what immigration is about.
>> Can I agree with you? We don't in this
country value citizenship enough. I
think we should encourage people to have
more civics lessons in schools,
understand American history and
constitution much more. Here's what's
the irony is I'm sitting in a room today
where I've met a bunch of people
claiming to be Native Americans who hate
everything America stood for for
centuries.
>> I think they stand much closer to the
America that we originally had. And I
think that's a big disagree if there had
any clue what that was like. And you
know things about that America,
>> but you've agreed to dismantling that
America as long as it's legal.
>> You have. You're the person who came
here and made your argument
taking away an amendment of the
Constitution. I didn't. I said keep the
Second Amendment.
>> I'm an originalist. I think we should
interpret it the way it was probably
originally interpreted.
>> All right, guys. That's time.
with your coach. Thank you very much,
man. Appreciate it.
>> I thought it would be an interesting
exercise in trying to understand what
genuine farright conservative folks
think. And it was kind of disturbing to
see that they think what I thought they
think and they were happy to say it out
loud. I am disappointed that I had to
sit across from people who believe in
white genocide, who believe I'm not a
citizen. Multiple people here said I
should be deported. One of them was even
the child of immigrants, which I found
bizarre. Obviously, we were way
outclassed. Like we're not uh
professional debaters. I don't think
anyone in this room was. Maybe one or
two people. And clearly Manny, he does
this for a living, right? He's a
journalist. So he's really good at what
he does.
>> Hassan was pretty good at, you know,
taking cheap shots, trying to like, you
know, derail people from their from
their arguments, you know, trying to
like pit me against, you know, some of
the people that wouldn't like people of
my color to be in the United States,
which is irrelevant.
>> I think one person said as he walked
off, you'll be the first to go. Uh which
is ominous and racist. I think that was
a disheartening and particularly
discouraging because it just felt like
it was fitting into a stereotype that
we're trying to fight against, which is
like we actually have arguments. We can
provide good reason and that rhetoric
just pushes that far away.
>> I am, I guess, a far-right Republican,
but as I learned today, not as far right
as I thought I was. You know, someone
gets up and they're just like, "Yeah, I
mean, I guess I just want to have like
autocracy forever and Christian
nationalism or just being like, yeah,
I'm racist." And to me, that's very
foreign of a concept. While I didn't,
you know, disagree with most of the
people in the circle, it did bother me
at times, you know, to see them um say
mean things, there's not really a reason
to do that. But it also upset me when
Medie said, you know, I'm not willing to
debate with those people. Free speech
doesn't mean you need to give
credibility or oxygen or a platform to
people who don't agree in human
equality.
>> I I hear Medy's point about not giving
them a platform, but the thing is, if
you stop giving them a platform, they
don't just go away and change their
mind. And then you tell the rest of
society, no one exists who thinks like
that. And that's not true.
>> I do like to debate people, even people
I disagree with. I try and avoid bad
faith folks. I think some of the folks
today were bad faith. You know, I'm
anti-conservative, right? I don't
support conservative views on taxation.
I don't support conservative views on
immigration. But the people here today
were way beyond conservatives. This is
open authoritarianism. And this is what
is being normalized and mainstreamed in
our country by people in power, by the
media, by people who don't know any